<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Encouragement on Bible Research</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/encouragement/</link><description>Recent content in Encouragement on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/encouragement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On Spiritual Regrowth and New Year's Resolutions</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/do-something/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/do-something/</guid><description>A new year begins and my life is busier than ever before. I now have less time to study Scripture and have more responsibilities outside of the realm of scriptural and theological studies. I used to be able to study Scripture and wrestle with theological questions for hours and hours, but now have half the time, at best, that I used to have. When I studied for long hours, I enjoyed learning about God from His word and felt closer to God, even though my studies raised a number of profound theological and philosophical questions.</description></item><item><title>Judge Not the Lord by Feeble Sense, but Trust Him for His Grace</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/judge-not-the-lord-by-feeble-sense/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/judge-not-the-lord-by-feeble-sense/</guid><description>God moves in a mysterious way His wonders to perform; He plants His footsteps in the sea, And rides upon the storm.
Deep in unfathomable mines Of never-failing skill He treasures up His bright designs, And works His sovereign will.
Ye fearful saints, fresh courage take, The clouds ye so much dread Are big with mercy, and shall break In blessings on your head.
Judge not the Lord by feeble sense, But trust Him for His grace; Behind a frowning providence He hides a smiling face.</description></item><item><title>"For our sake also" - The Beauty and Grace of Divine Revelation</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/romans-4-23-and-24/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/romans-4-23-and-24/</guid><description>I was reading the book of Romans and Romans 4:23-25 jumped out at me; it reads:
&amp;ldquo;Now not for his sake only was it written that it was credited to him, but for our sake also, to whom it will be credited, as those who believe in Him who raised Jesus our Lord from the dead, He who was delivered over because of our transgressions, and was raised because of our justification.</description></item></channel></rss>