<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sin on Bible Research</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/sin/</link><description>Recent content in Sin on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/sin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>False Grounds for Assurance of Salvation (part 1)</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/false-grounds-for-assurance-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/false-grounds-for-assurance-1/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Oh listen, do you love the Word of God? There&amp;rsquo;s no greater proof that you have really passed from death unto life than if you have an insatiable love for the Word of God.&amp;quot;1 Preface A Warning Before continuing, I encourage you to read the warning here.
If you are looking for the grounds of assurance of salvation (the means by which we can know that we are saved), I don&amp;rsquo;t have any to offer you right now and sincerely ask that you stop reading.</description></item><item><title>Struggling Against Sin</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/fighting-sin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/fighting-sin/</guid><description>The following was originally written on April 23, 2015:
Today. What a sweet word! Even on the worst days, it is such a sweet reminder that I have been granted this day, these hours as a stewardship and a blessing. It has been one of those tough days. I have really been struggling against sin and, while I have not given in, the grind and struggle is really exhausting. The resistance seems to take more of a toll than the sin itself.</description></item><item><title>Fighting Sin by Serving</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/fight-sin-by-serving/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/fight-sin-by-serving/</guid><description>I was reading Galatians 5:13 recently and this jumped out at me:
For you were called to freedom, brethren; only do not turn your freedom into an opportunity for the flesh, but through love serve one another.
In our efforts to glorify God and fight sin, one helpful strategy that I pull from this verse is to be busy serving one another. This has the dual benefits of keeping you busy and focusing your efforts on serving Christ and His church.</description></item><item><title>The Audacity of Man-made Religion</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/the-audacity-of-manmade-religion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/the-audacity-of-manmade-religion/</guid><description>One of the clear themes throughout the Bible is that it is God who defines how His creation must/should interact with Him. We are in no position (that is, we have no authority) to come to God on our own terms. If there is a God that is anything like the one described in the Bible, He has the inherit right, authority, and power to demand how we should relate to Him.</description></item><item><title>Please Pass the Pomegranate. Understanding the Nature of Sin in Genesis 3.</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/understanding-sin-from-genesis3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/understanding-sin-from-genesis3/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The Devil Made Me Do It&amp;rdquo;? First, consider who or what was involved in making Eve sin. One of the answers is clearly Satan in the form of the serpent (see Genesis 3:1). It is Satan who asks the infamous question &amp;ldquo;Hath God said&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; and causes Eve to doubt the words of God. It is important to recognize, however, that Satan is not the only thing that drives Eve to sin.</description></item></channel></rss>