<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sin on Bible Research</title>
    <link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/sin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sin on Bible Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/sin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Audacity of Man-made Religion</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/the-audacity-of-manmade-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/the-audacity-of-manmade-religion/</guid>
      <description>Man-made religion is futile and abhorrent for a few reasons, but one, particular horror towers above the rest. Behind man-made religion is the arrogant declaration that we define the terms of our relationship with God. Thus, it is impossible for man-made religions to worship anything but man himself.
One of the clear themes throughout the Bible is that it is God who defines how His creation must/should interact with Him. We are in no position (that is, we have no authority) to come to God on our own terms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please Pass the Pomegranate. Understanding the Nature of Sin in Genesis 3.</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/understanding-sin-from-genesis3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/understanding-sin-from-genesis3/</guid>
      <description>Just three short chapters into the narrative of God&amp;rsquo;s redemptive plan, we find Adam and Eve in the Garden of Eden, clothed with fig leaves and damning themselves and their children to a life separated from God. There are two observations about the story in Genesis 3 that I wish to make which will help us better understand the nature of sin.
First, consider who or what was involved in making Eve sin.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>