<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Matthew on Bible Research</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/tags/matthew/</link><description>Recent content in Matthew on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bible.hightower.space/tags/matthew/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jesus' Words on Forgiveness (Part 1 - Book of Matthew)</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/jesus-on-forgiveness-matthew/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/jesus-on-forgiveness-matthew/</guid><description>Preface I have two goals for you, my reader, in this post:
I would like to challenge you with Jesus' words on forgiveness. Jesus is not flippant or trivial on the topic of forgiveness and he attributes a weight and significance to forgiveness that is, I think, often lessened. I hope you will consider the practical implications of Jesus' words for your own life. In the words of Paul: Let all bitterness and wrath and anger and clamor and slander be put away from you, along with all malice.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Temptation of Jesus in Light of Matthew 3:17</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/temptation-of-jesus-matthew/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/temptation-of-jesus-matthew/</guid><description>I recently heard a sermon on the temptation of Jesus (Matthew 4:1-11) in which the pastor said something that caught my attention, got me thinking, and led me to what I think is a deeper, richer understanding of this passage. While the pastor did not say what I am about to say explicitly, he hinted in its general direction and I am very grateful not just for this sermon, but also for his faithful ministry of the word of God.</description></item></channel></rss>