<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Salvation on Bible Research</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/tags/salvation/</link><description>Recent content in Salvation on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bible.hightower.space/tags/salvation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Must I Do to be Saved?</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/how-can-man-be-saved/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/how-can-man-be-saved/</guid><description>This blog post contains what I consider to be big, weighty questions (with very few answers). If you choose to keep reading, please skim this post first: https://bible.hightower.space/posts/2020-warning/.
What must I do to be saved?
Seriously, what must I do to be saved? I&amp;rsquo;m so confused and overwhelmed by a whirl-wind of comments and responses on this question (both from inside and outside the Bible) that I honestly don&amp;rsquo;t know what the answer is right now.</description></item><item><title>False Grounds for Assurance of Salvation (part 1)</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/false-grounds-for-assurance-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/false-grounds-for-assurance-1/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Oh listen, do you love the Word of God? There&amp;rsquo;s no greater proof that you have really passed from death unto life than if you have an insatiable love for the Word of God.&amp;quot;1 Preface A Warning Before continuing, I encourage you to read the warning here.
If you are looking for the grounds of assurance of salvation (the means by which we can know that we are saved), I don&amp;rsquo;t have any to offer you right now and sincerely ask that you stop reading.</description></item><item><title>Pope Clement I on Salvation</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/first-pope-message/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/first-pope-message/</guid><description>Here is an excerpt from Pope Clement I in his First Epistle to the Corinthian Church:
&amp;ldquo;All these [referring to Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob], therefore, were highly honoured, and made great, not for their own sake, or for their own works, or for the righteousness which they wrought, but through the operation of His will. And we, too, being called by His will in Christ Jesus, are not justified by ourselves, nor by our own wisdom, or understanding, or godliness, or works which we have wrought in holiness of heart; but by that faith through which, from the beginning, Almighty God has justified all men; to whom be glory for ever and ever.</description></item><item><title>Three Aspects of Saving Faith</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/three-aspects-of-faith/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/three-aspects-of-faith/</guid><description>Introduction The three aspects of saving faith identified by the reformers are notitia, assensus, and fiducia.1For the reformers, saving faith was made up of each of these aspects. Possessing one or two of them does not mean you are saved. All three are necessary and are together sufficient for salvation. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at each of these aspects in more detail.
Three Aspects of Saving Faith Notitia Notitia refers to the comprehension of data or content that is to be believed.</description></item><item><title>Dialog About Assurance of Salvation</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/assurance-of-salvation-dialogue/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/assurance-of-salvation-dialogue/</guid><description>May: I was raised in the church and I understand that Bible teaches that believers can know that they are saved with certainty. I know 1 John discusses what is looks like to be a Christian and how we can know we are saved (for example, 1 John 5:13). I want to &amp;ldquo;know that [I] have eternal life&amp;rdquo;, but I&amp;rsquo;m having a hard time reconciling the claims of assurance in 1 John with some other truths from scripture.</description></item><item><title>Three Evidences that Baptism Is Not Necessary for Salvation</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/baptism-and-salvation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/baptism-and-salvation/</guid><description>There are some passages in scripture which appear, at first glance, to be saying that baptism is necessary for salvation (for example Mark 16:16, Acts 2:37-38, Galatians 3:27). In reformed, protestant circles, there are counter-arguments given for all of these passages (which I think are convincing and have sound Biblical grounds). I here present, however, three evidences from scripture that salvation does not require baptism. I would be curious how someone who believes that baptism is required for salvation would respond (you can contact me if you are such a person).</description></item><item><title>Psalm 62: God's Unique Ability to Save, Satisfy, and Sustain</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/psalm-62/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/psalm-62/</guid><description>Background According to the superscription, Psalm 62 is a psalm of David. While there is no explicit, historical context for the psalm, it refers to those who &amp;ldquo;assail a man that you may murder him&amp;rdquo; (Psalm 62:3). There were multiple points in David&amp;rsquo;s life when people were seeking to kill him, so this psalm could have been inspired by many of the events in David&amp;rsquo;s life.
Structure The psalm breaks down into five sections:</description></item></channel></rss>