<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Why on Bible Research</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/tags/why/</link><description>Recent content in Why on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bible.hightower.space/tags/why/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Should I Read the Old Testament?</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/why-read-ot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/why-read-ot/</guid><description>For the time being, I&amp;rsquo;m going to answer this question by looking at what the New Testament says about the Old Testament. So what does the New Testament have to say about the Old Testament?
The Old Testament&amp;hellip;
Predicts/points to Christ (Luke 24:44-47) Is sufficient to bring about salvation (Luke 16:19-31 (especially 29-31), 2 Timothy 3:15) Was written for our instruction (Romans 15:4, 1 Corinthians 10:11, Luke 17:32) Was written for our encouragement (Romans 15:4) (as part of scripture) Is profitable for teaching, reproof, correction, and training in righteousness (2 Timothy 3:16-17) Is fulfilled in/by Christ (2 Corinthians 1:20)</description></item><item><title>Why Should We Pray?</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/why-pray/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 05:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/why-pray/</guid><description>Reasons to Pray Scripture gives numerous reasons why we should pray. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at a few examples. I&amp;rsquo;m going to split the reasons why we should pray into two categories:
We should pray in order to:
Glorify God Enjoy Him forever This way of breaking these reasons down is based on the first question and answer of the Westminster Confession of Faith.
&amp;ldquo;to glorify God&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; We should pray because prayer glorifies God.</description></item><item><title>Practical Spiritual Disciplines: Introduction</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-why/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-why/</guid><description>Motivation In Western, conservative Churches, our knowledge often far exceeds our living. That is, we usually know far more about theology than we live out in our lives. When it comes down to it, most of us know what we are supposed to do (for example: pray, read your Bible, evangelize, etc.) and why we are supposed to do those things, but we still are not doing the things we should.</description></item><item><title>Blog Objectives</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/blog-objectives/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/blog-objectives/</guid><description>The basic objective of this blog is to give me a platform to communicate some of the thoughts and observations I have that don&amp;rsquo;t fit well into the Bible Notes project. My goal in voicing some of these thoughts is to provide more resources that will strengthen the Church and produce mature, thoughtful followers of Christ. It also gives me the chance to hone my writing and communication skills (which I then hope to use to strengthen the Church).</description></item></channel></rss>