<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Consequentialism on Bible Research</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/consequentialism/</link><description>Recent content in Consequentialism on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/consequentialism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Guidelines for Using Old Testament Passages Well</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/guidelines-for-using-the-old-testament-well/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/guidelines-for-using-the-old-testament-well/</guid><description>Disclaimer Before reading the article below, I recommend you take a look at my post on Why I Cite Specific Examples. I address this issue humbly and with the utmost respect and love for all parties involved. None of us are perfect or perfectly consistent; it would not shock me if the whistle were blown on me for the same hermeneutic fouls I penalize below. I stand open to correction and am bold only because I believe that handling the Word of God is like donning a space-suit before going on a space walk; our very lives depend on it and it ought to be done with the greatest care and accuracy possible.</description></item><item><title>A Consequentialist Hermeneutic</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/consequentialist-hermeneutic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/consequentialist-hermeneutic/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Consequentialism, as its name suggests, is the view that normative properties depend only on consequences. This general approach can be applied at different levels to different normative properties of different kinds of things&amp;hellip;&amp;quot;1 A Consequentialist Hermeneutic Defining A Consequentialist Hermeneutic I believe that many conservative, evangelical churches today are comfortable with bad hermeneutics because because they suffer from &amp;ldquo;A Consequentialist Hermeneutic&amp;rdquo;. This disease is the attitude that any hermeneutic which leads to a true conclusion must be correct.</description></item></channel></rss>