<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Doubts on Bible Research</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/doubts/</link><description>Recent content in Doubts on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/doubts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Deadly Lifestyle (part 2): How I Feel About Church and the Bible Right Now</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/deadly-lifestyle-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/deadly-lifestyle-part-2/</guid><description>This is a follow up to the first &amp;ldquo;Deadly Lifestyle&amp;rdquo; post.
The Situation It is very difficult for me to read/study the Bible right now. Here is what happens almost every time I open the Bible:
I pray As you will see below, I really need help! I start reading for example, I recently read Acts 8 I notice something fascinating/interesting In Acts 8, it is interesting that Simon the Magician is said to have &amp;ldquo;believed&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;being baptized, he continued on with Philip&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (Acts 8:13) and yet Peter harshly rebukes him for trying to buy the free gift of God and calls him to repent (Acts 8:21-23).</description></item><item><title>A Deadly Lifestyle: How I Feel About Church and the Bible Right Now</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/deadly-lifestyle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/deadly-lifestyle/</guid><description>For the past year, going to church and reading the bible has felt like this:
I am shackled in a prison. I am periodically given enough &amp;lsquo;food&amp;rsquo; to live (I say &amp;lsquo;food&amp;rsquo; because some of it is inedible or undesirable (raw, rotting meat, bones, lard, etc.))&amp;hellip; but getting the food is difficult because the shackle on my neck has small protrusions or hooks on the inside designed to create small lacerations on my neck if I strain against the shackle too much.</description></item><item><title>Dealing with Doubts</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/dealing-with-doubts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/dealing-with-doubts/</guid><description>Here are some practical principles I have come up with:
Don&amp;rsquo;t wallow in doubt Don&amp;rsquo;t stay isolated (and don&amp;rsquo;t isolate yourself) With respect to God&amp;rsquo;s word, be (James 1): quick to listen slow to speak slow to become angry Pray like crazy! - Follow the example of David, James 1, Jesus, and the Apostles (see also some thoughts on prayerlessness) Trust God&amp;rsquo;s sovereignty Address the issues head-on When in doubt, trust the boundaries and means of Grace God has given No friendly-fire!</description></item></channel></rss>