<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Satan on Bible Research</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/satan/</link><description>Recent content in Satan on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/satan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding the Temptation of Jesus in Light of Matthew 3:17</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/temptation-of-jesus-matthew/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/temptation-of-jesus-matthew/</guid><description>I recently heard a sermon on the temptation of Jesus (Matthew 4:1-11) in which the pastor said something that caught my attention, got me thinking, and led me to what I think is a deeper, richer understanding of this passage. While the pastor did not say what I am about to say explicitly, he hinted in its general direction and I am very grateful not just for this sermon, but also for his faithful ministry of the word of God.</description></item><item><title>Satan or Serpent? Understanding the Protevangelium.</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/defending-protevangelium/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/defending-protevangelium/</guid><description>I was recently reading through Genesis and paused when I got to Genesis 3:14-15. I have always been taught that Genesis 3:15 was directed not at the physical serpent (that is, the creature itself), but the spiritual &amp;lsquo;serpent&amp;rsquo; (who is Satan). But in my recent reading, I asked myself: Are we right to interpret Genesis 3:15 in this way? This post contains my conclusion on the subject after thought and investigation.</description></item><item><title>Please Pass the Pomegranate. Understanding the Nature of Sin in Genesis 3.</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/understanding-sin-from-genesis3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/understanding-sin-from-genesis3/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The Devil Made Me Do It&amp;rdquo;? First, consider who or what was involved in making Eve sin. One of the answers is clearly Satan in the form of the serpent (see Genesis 3:1). It is Satan who asks the infamous question &amp;ldquo;Hath God said&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; and causes Eve to doubt the words of God. It is important to recognize, however, that Satan is not the only thing that drives Eve to sin.</description></item><item><title>Was Satan Suprised?</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/was-satan-suprised/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/was-satan-suprised/</guid><description>Was Satan surprised&amp;hellip; too busy looking at Job to see Jesus?
too busy deceiving the eves to notice the ave&amp;hellip; maria who, through no merit of her own and though a sinner such as I, was blessed to bring into the fallen, dirty world one who, in ages past, had made the oceans whirl and rivers swirl?
Was Satan surprised&amp;hellip; too busy roaming about on the earth?
too busy building Babel to notice a babe in Bethlehem&amp;hellip; who, by submission to His Father’s will and because of His great love with which He loved us, would bless sinners with reconciliation and an inheritance?</description></item></channel></rss>