<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jesus Christ on Bible Research</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/jesus-christ/</link><description>Recent content in Jesus Christ on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/jesus-christ/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Man Worth Trusting</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/a-man-worth-trusting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/a-man-worth-trusting/</guid><description>I was studying John 18:1-11 with some friends and was struck by something one of my friends said. We had just discussed John 18:3 where the word &amp;ldquo;σπεῖραν&amp;rdquo;1could mean either a tenth of a legion (a legion was 6,000 men, so this would mean 600 men were coming to arrest Jesus) or used as Polybius referring to 200 men2. Either way, you likely have a good number of men coming to arrest Jesus.</description></item><item><title>Why Every Christian Must Fight and Flee Pornography</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/why-stop-watching-pornography/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/why-stop-watching-pornography/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s cut to the chase&amp;hellip; pornography has been cited as an epidemic of our age.1It is ubiquitous and easily accessible. There is a lot which can be said on the subject from many different angles and different perspectives, but for now, I&amp;rsquo;m going to present four motives that should animate every Christian to fight and flee pornography. I hope to discuss how to fight and flee pornography at some point, but for now, we&amp;rsquo;ll deal with why.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts On Prayerlessness</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/excuses-for-prayerlessness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/excuses-for-prayerlessness/</guid><description>My Excuses When it comes to my excuses for not praying, I have three, solid pleas which I regret to admit have often freed me from the bond of love and intimacy with God:
&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m too busy.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m working on things which are more important than prayer.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t need to pray right now.&amp;rdquo; (i.e. &amp;ldquo;My relationship with God is ok right now and I don&amp;rsquo;t need to spend time with Him.</description></item></channel></rss>