<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Interpretation on Bible Research</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/tags/interpretation/</link><description>Recent content in Interpretation on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bible.hightower.space/tags/interpretation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why I Use a Normal, Literal, and Grammatical Hermeneutic</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/why-literal-gramatical-hermenuetic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/why-literal-gramatical-hermenuetic/</guid><description>Definitions I believe that definitions and the meaning of words are important.1In the future, I intend to more thoroughly define and defend my hermeneutic (and define what I mean by &amp;lsquo;normal, literal, and grammatical&amp;rsquo;), but for now, I am just going to take for granted that my audience understands what I mean when I say &amp;ldquo;normal, literal, and grammatical hermeneutic&amp;rdquo;. For the rest of this blog post, I will use the acronym NLG to represent a normal, literal, and grammatical hermeneutic.</description></item><item><title>A Starting Point for Hermeneutics</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/starting-point-hermenuetics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/starting-point-hermenuetics/</guid><description>Definitions and Objectives Before jumping into the post, let me first define a couple of the phrases in the abstract.
&amp;ldquo;common-sense starting point&amp;rdquo; To clarify the objective of this blog post, I am not seeking to establish a complete and robust foundation for a hermeneutic. This is why I&amp;rsquo;m calling it a &amp;ldquo;common-sense starting point&amp;rdquo;; this blog post takes for granted many philosophical assumptions. While I do not deny defending my presuppositions would be a useful endeavor, I am not going to undertake it here.</description></item><item><title>Satan or Serpent? Understanding the Protevangelium.</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/defending-protevangelium/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/defending-protevangelium/</guid><description>I was recently reading through Genesis and paused when I got to Genesis 3:14-15. I have always been taught that Genesis 3:15 was directed not at the physical serpent (that is, the creature itself), but the spiritual &amp;lsquo;serpent&amp;rsquo; (who is Satan). But in my recent reading, I asked myself: Are we right to interpret Genesis 3:15 in this way? This post contains my conclusion on the subject after thought and investigation.</description></item></channel></rss>