<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Church History on Bible Research</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/church-history/</link><description>Recent content in Church History on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/church-history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Church History Covenant</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/church-history/covenant/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/church-history/covenant/</guid><description>I, _____________________________, will strive with my utmost effort to listen, participate, read, and study to the utmost of my God-given abilities for the purpose of learning about the sovereign acts and works of God throughout the early centuries of the Church through the writings of and descriptions about men and women who claimed Christ as their Savior during the extent of the ISM Summer Study Series on Church History.
As part of the work for this study series, I covenant to read for a minimum of one (1) hour per day for the extent of this series.</description></item><item><title>Pope Clement I on Salvation</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/first-pope-message/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/first-pope-message/</guid><description>Here is an excerpt from Pope Clement I in his First Epistle to the Corinthian Church:
&amp;ldquo;All these [referring to Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob], therefore, were highly honoured, and made great, not for their own sake, or for their own works, or for the righteousness which they wrought, but through the operation of His will. And we, too, being called by His will in Christ Jesus, are not justified by ourselves, nor by our own wisdom, or understanding, or godliness, or works which we have wrought in holiness of heart; but by that faith through which, from the beginning, Almighty God has justified all men; to whom be glory for ever and ever.</description></item><item><title>Why I Use a Normal, Literal, and Grammatical Hermeneutic</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/why-literal-gramatical-hermenuetic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/why-literal-gramatical-hermenuetic/</guid><description>Definitions I believe that definitions and the meaning of words are important.1In the future, I intend to more thoroughly define and defend my hermeneutic (and define what I mean by &amp;lsquo;normal, literal, and grammatical&amp;rsquo;), but for now, I am just going to take for granted that my audience understands what I mean when I say &amp;ldquo;normal, literal, and grammatical hermeneutic&amp;rdquo;. For the rest of this blog post, I will use the acronym NLG to represent a normal, literal, and grammatical hermeneutic.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Relationships between the Five 'Solas' of the Reformation.</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/five-solae/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/five-solae/</guid><description>The principles behind the reformation are often summarized in five exclusive statements deemed &amp;lsquo;Solae&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Solas&amp;rsquo;:
Sola Scriptura (&amp;ldquo;Scripture alone&amp;rdquo;) Sola Fide (&amp;ldquo;faith alone&amp;rdquo;) Sola Gratia (&amp;ldquo;grace alone&amp;rdquo;) Solus Christus (&amp;ldquo;Christ alone&amp;rdquo;) Soli Deo gloria (&amp;ldquo;glory to God alone&amp;rdquo;) These statements have been used both to describe what Luther and the other reformers believed as well as to discern what the Bible does and does not teach. Because we often see the five solas listed out in bullet points, we often do not consider the relationships between them.</description></item></channel></rss>