<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Bible Research</title>
    <link>//localhost:8000/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Bible Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//localhost:8000/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Spiritual Disciplines: Introduction</title>
      <link>//localhost:8000/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:8000/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines_0/</guid>
      <description>This is the introduction to a series which gives practical steps for practicing the &amp;ldquo;spiritual disciplines&amp;rdquo; (activities like prayer, reading your Bible, serving the Church, etc). In this post, I lay out the motivation and objectives for this series.
Motivation In Western, conservative Churches, our knowledge often far exceeds our living. That is, we usually know far more about theology than we live out in our lives. When it comes down to it, most of us know what we are supposed to do (for example: pray, read your Bible, evangelize, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Performative Nature of Wisdom Literature</title>
      <link>//localhost:8000/posts/performative-wisdom-lit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:8000/posts/performative-wisdom-lit/</guid>
      <description>Wisdom literature in the Bible (books like Job, Proverbs, and Ecclesiastes) is not easy to understand&amp;hellip; and this is no accident. It is designed not only to show you what true wisdom is, but also to produce it within you. This is what makes wisdom literature performative.
In linguistics, performativity describes of the ability of communication (in any form) to do something.1 This is a break from the way we normally view language as a means of describing something or asking someone to do something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 62: God&#39;s Unique Ability to Save, Satisfy, and Sustain</title>
      <link>//localhost:8000/posts/psalm-62/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:8000/posts/psalm-62/</guid>
      <description>The record of human history demonstrates that God does three, wonderful things for mankind: He saves; He satisfies; He sustains. Psalm 62 celebrates these wonderful truths and emphasizes God&amp;rsquo;s unique ability to provide in each area.
Background According to the superscription, Psalm 62 is a psalm of David. While there is no explicit, historical context for the psalm, it refers to those who &amp;ldquo;assail a man that you may murder him&amp;rdquo; (Psalm 62:3).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you Wasting your Life?</title>
      <link>//localhost:8000/posts/dont-waste-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:8000/posts/dont-waste-your-life/</guid>
      <description>You only have one, short life. What is the most valuable thing you can do with it?
I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but one of my greatest fears is wasting my life. Getting to 60 years of age and realizing, with a hollow, sinking feeling in the pit of my stomach, that I haven&amp;rsquo;t done anything with my life.
The problem for many, myself included, is knowing what is the most valuable thing we can be doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you can read this... Thank a Teacher!</title>
      <link>//localhost:8000/posts/thank-your-teachers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:8000/posts/thank-your-teachers/</guid>
      <description>This week, take some time to thank a teacher or mentor you appreciate.
All it takes is a quick email, phone call, or even a text. Or better yet&amp;hellip; next time you see them, take some time to let them know how much you appreciate what they do for you. It is really hard to be a teacher and is often a thank-less endeavour which can get depressing over time. Even a short word of thanks can go great lengths to encourage your teacher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cain &amp; Abel</title>
      <link>//localhost:8000/posts/cain-and-abel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:8000/posts/cain-and-abel/</guid>
      <description>Why was Abel&amp;rsquo;s sacrifice accepted while Cain&amp;rsquo;s was not?
Genesis 4:1-15 describes the infamous story of Cain and Abel. In this story, two brothers, Cain (a &amp;ldquo;tiller of the ground&amp;rdquo;) and Abel (a &amp;ldquo;keeper of flocks&amp;rdquo;), bring a sacrifice before God (see Genesis 4:2-3). Verses three and four tell us that Cain brings &amp;ldquo;an offering of the fruit of the ground&amp;rdquo; and Abel brings &amp;ldquo;the firstlings of his flock and their fat portions&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 90: The Problem of God&#39;s Immanence</title>
      <link>//localhost:8000/posts/sovereign-and-immanent-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:8000/posts/sovereign-and-immanent-god/</guid>
      <description>Psalm 90 deals with one of the most basic challenges facing humanity: If there really is a sovereign, holy God who created everything and knows our every thought but is also immanent, how can man live and find meaning in living?
Before we begin, let&amp;rsquo;s define some of the terms with which we may not be familiar:
 Sovereignty of God: God&amp;rsquo;s absolute control and rule over everything.
Immanence of God: The tendency of God to relate with His creation and interact in human history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spies&#39; Bad Report</title>
      <link>//localhost:8000/posts/spies-bad-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:8000/posts/spies-bad-report/</guid>
      <description>In Numbers 13:25-33, the spies sent into the Promised Land return with a scouting report. There is some subtlety, however, to the way in which the report is described in the text that leads me to believe there is more to this account than is normally assumed. This post lays out what I believe to be the best understanding of the passage.
What is described below is, in my estimation, a well-supported theory, but a theory nonetheless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Audacity of Man-made Religion</title>
      <link>//localhost:8000/posts/the-audacity-of-manmade-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:8000/posts/the-audacity-of-manmade-religion/</guid>
      <description>Man-made religion is futile and abhorrent for a few reasons, but one, particular horror towers above the rest. Behind man-made religion is the arrogant declaration that we define the terms of our relationship with God. Thus, it is impossible for man-made religions to worship anything but man himself.
One of the clear themes throughout the Bible is that it is God who defines how His creation must/should interact with Him. We are in no position (that is, we have no authority) to come to God on our own terms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you are apathetic toward Leviticus.</title>
      <link>//localhost:8000/posts/leviticus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:8000/posts/leviticus/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s face it, Leviticus can be a hard book to read. It is probably the biggest killers of Bible reading plans. How can we get any value out of this book? In this post, I point out a couple mistakes we make when come to the book of Leviticus and suggest some ways to better understand and apply Leviticus.
Mistakes We often make two, critical mistakes when we read the book of Leviticus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Relationships between the Five &#39;Solas&#39; of the Reformation.</title>
      <link>//localhost:8000/posts/five-solae/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:8000/posts/five-solae/</guid>
      <description>Many protestants are very familiar with the five &amp;lsquo;solas&amp;rsquo; of the Reformation, but do you understand how they relate with one another?
The principles behind the reformation are often summarized in five exclusive statements deemed &amp;lsquo;Solae&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Solas&amp;rsquo;:
 Sola Scriptura (&amp;ldquo;Scripture alone&amp;rdquo;) Sola Fide (&amp;ldquo;faith alone&amp;rdquo;) Sola Gratia (&amp;ldquo;grace alone&amp;rdquo;) Solus Christus (&amp;ldquo;Christ alone&amp;rdquo;) Soli Deo gloria (&amp;ldquo;glory to God alone&amp;rdquo;)  These statements have been used both to describe what Luther and the other reformers believed as well as to discern what the Bible does and does not teach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passages for a Preliminary Understanding of the Plagues and the Exodus</title>
      <link>//localhost:8000/posts/israel-in-egypt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:8000/posts/israel-in-egypt/</guid>
      <description>When we think about Israel&amp;rsquo;s time in Egypt, the plagues, and Israel&amp;rsquo;s Exodus from Egypt, there are a few passages that are important to keep in mind.
 Genesis 15:13-16 - Israel&amp;rsquo;s slavery in Egypt is promised as well as God&amp;rsquo;s judgement on Egypt and Israel&amp;rsquo;s subsequent possessions. Genesis 50:25-26 (and Exodus 23:19) - Joseph asks, with faith in God&amp;rsquo;s promise, that his bones be taken out of Egypt and buried in the land promised to Israel by God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is Canaan Cursed Rather than Ham?</title>
      <link>//localhost:8000/posts/canaan-and-ham/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:8000/posts/canaan-and-ham/</guid>
      <description>Characteristic of the strange stories in Genesis, the story of Shem, Ham (and Canaan), and Japheth in Genesis 9:18-27 is the subject of much debate. Of particular interest is this: Why does Noah curse Canaan (Ham&amp;rsquo;s son) if Ham was the one who perpetrated the crime in question?
The text does not give us enough details to know exactly why, but I think there are a few things we can conclude from the passage:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch your Lingo!</title>
      <link>//localhost:8000/posts/watch-your-lingo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:8000/posts/watch-your-lingo/</guid>
      <description>We are living in what is quickly becoming a post-Christian culture. As such, pastors, teachers, leaders, and even lay Christians need to wake up to the reality that Christian jargon widely understood in previous generations is no longer understood by the vast majority of people under the age of 30.
Examples Last time communion was served at my Church, I heard the familiar phrase: &amp;ldquo;If you are not a believer, please let the elements pass you by&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Satan or Serpent? Understanding the Protevangelium.</title>
      <link>//localhost:8000/posts/defending-protevangelium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:8000/posts/defending-protevangelium/</guid>
      <description>Are we right to interpret Genesis 3:15 as applying to Satan?
I was recently reading through Genesis and paused when I got to Genesis 3:14-15. I have always been taught that Genesis 3:15 was directed not at the physical serpent (that is, the creature itself), but the spiritual &amp;lsquo;serpent&amp;rsquo; (who is Satan). But in my recent reading, I asked myself: Are we right to interpret Genesis 3:15 in this way?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please Pass the Pomegranate. Understanding the Nature of Sin in Genesis 3.</title>
      <link>//localhost:8000/posts/understanding-sin-from-genesis3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:8000/posts/understanding-sin-from-genesis3/</guid>
      <description>Just three short chapters into the narrative of God&amp;rsquo;s redemptive plan, we find Adam and Eve in the Garden of Eden, clothed with fig leaves and damning themselves and their children to a life separated from God. There are two observations about the story in Genesis 3 that I wish to make which will help us better understand the nature of sin.
First, consider who or what was involved in making Eve sin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Objectives</title>
      <link>//localhost:8000/posts/blog-objectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:8000/posts/blog-objectives/</guid>
      <description>What is the objective of this blog?
The basic objective of this blog is to give me a platform to communicate some of the thoughts and observations I have that don&amp;rsquo;t fit well into the Bible Notes project. My goal in voicing some of these thoughts is to provide more resources that will strengthen the Church and produce mature, thoughtful followers of Christ. It also gives me the chance to hone my writing and communication skills (which I then hope to use to strengthen the Church).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>