<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Leviticus on Bible Research</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/tags/leviticus/</link><description>Recent content in Leviticus on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bible.hightower.space/tags/leviticus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Guidelines for Using Old Testament Passages Well</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/guidelines-for-using-the-old-testament-well/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/guidelines-for-using-the-old-testament-well/</guid><description>Disclaimer Before reading the article below, I recommend you take a look at my post on Why I Cite Specific Examples. I address this issue humbly and with the utmost respect and love for all parties involved. None of us are perfect or perfectly consistent; it would not shock me if the whistle were blown on me for the same hermeneutic fouls I penalize below. I stand open to correction and am bold only because I believe that handling the Word of God is like donning a space-suit before going on a space walk; our very lives depend on it and it ought to be done with the greatest care and accuracy possible.</description></item><item><title>The Audacity of Man-made Religion</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/the-audacity-of-manmade-religion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/the-audacity-of-manmade-religion/</guid><description>One of the clear themes throughout the Bible is that it is God who defines how His creation must/should interact with Him. We are in no position (that is, we have no authority) to come to God on our own terms. If there is a God that is anything like the one described in the Bible, He has the inherit right, authority, and power to demand how we should relate to Him.</description></item><item><title>Why you are Apathetic Toward Leviticus</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/leviticus/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/leviticus/</guid><description>Mistakes We often make two, critical mistakes when we read the book of Leviticus. First, we are to busy looking for imperatives and applications that we miss the meaning (and, therefore, the real applications). Second, we isolate Leviticus and don&amp;rsquo;t read it as part of a larger story. Let us begin with the first issue.
We, Christians who hold the Bible as the sole authority for life and Godliness, must stop reading the Bible selfishly.</description></item></channel></rss>