<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spiritual Disciplines on Bible Research</title>
    <link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/spiritual-disciplines/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spiritual Disciplines on Bible Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/spiritual-disciplines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer Plan</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/prayer-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/prayer-plan/</guid>
      <description>I use it as a system for guiding my prayer life and I hope you find it helpful. Feel free to tweak and modify it as you see fit.
Basics There are two basic parts of this system:
 Requests Bible passages  The idea is that you split up your requests over a week and will have a specific Bible passage to guide your prayer each week. For example, let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a friend named Martha and you want to pray for her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Spiritual Disciplines: Prayer</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-prayer/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a series called Practical Spiritual Disciplines in which I will be discussing how to practice the spiritual disciplines.
The Question We all know prayer is important. Prayer is one of the most common topics throughout the Bible and Jesus Himself consistently made time out of His busy and effective ministry to pray (see Luke 5:16, 6:12, 9:28, 11:1, and 22:41 as some examples). If you think you are too busy or don&amp;rsquo;t need prayer, take a look at Jesus&amp;rsquo;s life and think again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Spiritual Disciplines: What are Spiritual Disciplines?</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-what/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a series called Practical Spiritual Disciplines which is designed to show you what tools and activities God has given us to grow and how we can practices these disciplines in our daily lives.
 “We are far too easily pleased.”
~ C.S. Lewis, The Weight of Glory
 Definition A spiritual discipline is an activity, which ought to be a habit, that the Bible prescribes for Christians to help them grow spiritually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Spiritual Disciplines: Introduction</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-why/</guid>
      <description>Motivation In Western, conservative Churches, our knowledge often far exceeds our living. That is, we usually know far more about theology than we live out in our lives. When it comes down to it, most of us know what we are supposed to do (for example: pray, read your Bible, evangelize, etc.) and why we are supposed to do those things, but we still are not doing the things we should.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>