<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spiritual Disciplines on Bible Research</title>
    <link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/spiritual-disciplines/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spiritual Disciplines on Bible Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/spiritual-disciplines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Prayer</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/thoughts-on-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/thoughts-on-prayer/</guid>
      <description>In studying prayer recently, I have a few more thoughts that did not find a home among the other writings on prayer. I have captured them below in no particular order other than the sequence in which they were brought to mind.
Pray for Your Enemies Let us not forget that we are called to &amp;ldquo;love your enemies and pray for those who persecute you&amp;rdquo; (Matthew 5:44). Notice a couple of things here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer Plan</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/prayer-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/prayer-plan/</guid>
      <description>I use it as a system for guiding my prayer life and I hope you find it helpful. Feel free to modify it as you see fit.
Basics There are two basic parts of this system:
 Prayer items Bible passages  The idea is that you split up your prayer items over a week and will have a specific Bible passage to guide your prayer each week. For example, let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a friend named Martha and you want to pray for her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Spiritual Disciplines: Prayer</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-prayer/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a series called Practical Spiritual Disciplines in which I will be discussing how to practice the spiritual disciplines.
 Since [prayer] is a duty of such absolute necessity for all and of such universal use, it is fitting we should all know how to perform it aright, that it may be accepted by the great God, and become a delightful and profitable exercise to our own souls and to those that join with us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Spiritual Disciplines: What are Spiritual Disciplines?</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-what/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a series called Practical Spiritual Disciplines which is designed to show you what tools and activities God has given us to grow and how we can practices these disciplines in our daily lives.
 “We are far too easily pleased.”
~ C.S. Lewis, The Weight of Glory
 Definition A spiritual discipline is an activity, which ought to be a habit, that the Bible prescribes for Christians to help them grow spiritually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Spiritual Disciplines: Introduction</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-why/</guid>
      <description>Motivation In Western, conservative Churches, our knowledge often far exceeds our living. That is, we usually know far more about theology than we live out in our lives. When it comes down to it, most of us know what we are supposed to do (for example: pray, read your Bible, evangelize, etc.) and why we are supposed to do those things, but we still are not doing the things we should.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>