<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spiritual Disciplines on Bible Research</title>
    <link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/spiritual-disciplines/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spiritual Disciplines on Bible Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/spiritual-disciplines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer Plan</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/prayer-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/prayer-plan/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m laying out a system I use to help me pray for other people and requests consistently over time while not getting bored because I&amp;rsquo;m praying for the same thing or getting frustrated because I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to pray for. I use it as a system for guiding my prayer life and I hope you find it helpful. Feel free to tweak and modify it as you see fit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Spiritual Disciplines: Prayer</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-prayer/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m starting a series called Practical Spiritual Disciplines in which I will be discussing how to practice the spiritual disciplines. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to discuss how we can make prayer a regular part of our lives.
The Question We all know prayer is important. Prayer is one of the most common topics throughout the Bible and Jesus Himself consistently made time out of His busy and effective ministry to pray (see Luke 5:16, 6:12, 9:28, 11:1, and 22:41 as some examples).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Spiritual Disciplines: What are Spiritual Disciplines?</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-what/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m starting a series called Practical Spiritual Disciplines which is designed to show you what tools and activities God has given us to grow and how we can practices these disciplines in our daily lives. This post is designed to discuss what I mean by a &amp;ldquo;spiritual discipline&amp;rdquo; and to look at some of the spiritual disciplines presented in the Bible.
 “We are far too easily pleased.”
~ C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Spiritual Disciplines: Introduction</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-why/</guid>
      <description>This is the introduction to a series which gives practical steps for practicing the &amp;ldquo;spiritual disciplines&amp;rdquo; (activities like prayer, reading your Bible, serving the Church, etc). In this post, I lay out the motivation and objectives for this series.
Motivation In Western, conservative Churches, our knowledge often far exceeds our living. That is, we usually know far more about theology than we live out in our lives. When it comes down to it, most of us know what we are supposed to do (for example: pray, read your Bible, evangelize, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>