<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hermeneutics on Bible Research</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/hermeneutics/</link><description>Recent content in Hermeneutics on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/hermeneutics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Does Every Word in the Bible Only Have One Meaning?</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/words-only-one-meaning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/words-only-one-meaning/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;A fundamental principle in grammatico-historical exposition is that words and sentences can have but one signification in one and the same connection. The moment we neglect this principle we drift out upon a sea of uncertainty and conjecture. It is commonly assumed by the universal sense of mankind that unless one designedly put forth a riddle, he will so speak as to convey his meaning as clearly as possible to others.</description></item><item><title>Questions about Exegetical Preaching</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/questions-about-exegetical-preaching/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/questions-about-exegetical-preaching/</guid><description>The subsequent blog post captures a few of my questions about exegetical preaching; at the time of writing, these are open questions and I do not have answers to them. I articulate these questions with the intention of getting them answered. If/when I get them answered, I will write another post providing the answers and will post it here.
I write this with the utmost respect for all, gospel-preaching pastors. I am in no way attempting to insult or undermine their work.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on Article VIII of the Chicago Statement on Biblical Hermeneutics</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/article-8-chicago-hermeneutics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/article-8-chicago-hermeneutics/</guid><description>Article VIII of the Chicago Statement on Biblical Hermeneutics states:
We affirm that the Bible contains teachings and mandates which apply to all cultural and situational contexts and other mandates which the Bible itself shows apply only to particular situations.
We deny that the distinction between the universal and particular mandates of Scripture can be determined by cultural and situational factors. We further deny that universal mandates may ever be treated as culturally or situationally relative.</description></item><item><title>Guidelines for Using Old Testament Passages Well</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/guidelines-for-using-the-old-testament-well/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/guidelines-for-using-the-old-testament-well/</guid><description>Disclaimer Before reading the article below, I recommend you take a look at my post on Why I Cite Specific Examples. I address this issue humbly and with the utmost respect and love for all parties involved. None of us are perfect or perfectly consistent; it would not shock me if the whistle were blown on me for the same hermeneutic fouls I penalize below. I stand open to correction and am bold only because I believe that handling the Word of God is like donning a space-suit before going on a space walk; our very lives depend on it and it ought to be done with the greatest care and accuracy possible.</description></item><item><title>Truth and Validity in Hermeneutics</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/truth-and-validity-of-hermeneutics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/truth-and-validity-of-hermeneutics/</guid><description>Disclaimer What I present here is a nascent concept and one that has probably already been articulated. If you have any feedback or know of someone who has already introduced a concept like the one below, please let me know. Thanks!
Abstract Part of the confusion about hermeneutics, especially in the world of conservative evangelicalism, is a failure to differentiate between the truth of a statement (whether the statement corresponds with objective reality) and the validity of a statement (whether the statement is actually found in the text).</description></item><item><title>A Consequentialist Hermeneutic</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/consequentialist-hermeneutic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/consequentialist-hermeneutic/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Consequentialism, as its name suggests, is the view that normative properties depend only on consequences. This general approach can be applied at different levels to different normative properties of different kinds of things&amp;hellip;&amp;quot;1 A Consequentialist Hermeneutic Defining A Consequentialist Hermeneutic I believe that many conservative, evangelical churches today are comfortable with bad hermeneutics because because they suffer from &amp;ldquo;A Consequentialist Hermeneutic&amp;rdquo;. This disease is the attitude that any hermeneutic which leads to a true conclusion must be correct.</description></item><item><title>Why I Use a Normal, Literal, and Grammatical Hermeneutic</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/why-literal-gramatical-hermenuetic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/why-literal-gramatical-hermenuetic/</guid><description>Definitions I believe that definitions and the meaning of words are important.1In the future, I intend to more thoroughly define and defend my hermeneutic (and define what I mean by &amp;lsquo;normal, literal, and grammatical&amp;rsquo;), but for now, I am just going to take for granted that my audience understands what I mean when I say &amp;ldquo;normal, literal, and grammatical hermeneutic&amp;rdquo;. For the rest of this blog post, I will use the acronym NLG to represent a normal, literal, and grammatical hermeneutic.</description></item><item><title>A Starting Point for Hermeneutics</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/starting-point-hermenuetics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/starting-point-hermenuetics/</guid><description>Definitions and Objectives Before jumping into the post, let me first define a couple of the phrases in the abstract.
&amp;ldquo;common-sense starting point&amp;rdquo; To clarify the objective of this blog post, I am not seeking to establish a complete and robust foundation for a hermeneutic. This is why I&amp;rsquo;m calling it a &amp;ldquo;common-sense starting point&amp;rdquo;; this blog post takes for granted many philosophical assumptions. While I do not deny defending my presuppositions would be a useful endeavor, I am not going to undertake it here.</description></item></channel></rss>