<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Love on Bible Research</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/tags/love/</link><description>Recent content in Love on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bible.hightower.space/tags/love/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why I Cite Specific People, Books, and Sermons</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/disclaimer-for-citing-specific-examples/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/disclaimer-for-citing-specific-examples/</guid><description>Update (Summer 2020) In the past, I have cited specific examples (usually youtube clips) of issues and concerns I have with evangelicalism. I am no longer going to do this and have taken down mosts of my posts containing links to statements made by pastors. I do not object to the reasons for citing specific examples as detailed below and I see the merits of doing so, but I am unable to maintain a humble, gentle, peaceful heart when I cite specific examples, so I will no longer be doing so (at least not on a regular basis).</description></item><item><title>Why Every Christian Must Fight and Flee Pornography</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/why-stop-watching-pornography/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/why-stop-watching-pornography/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s cut to the chase&amp;hellip; pornography has been cited as an epidemic of our age.1It is ubiquitous and easily accessible. There is a lot which can be said on the subject from many different angles and different perspectives, but for now, I&amp;rsquo;m going to present four motives that should animate every Christian to fight and flee pornography. I hope to discuss how to fight and flee pornography at some point, but for now, we&amp;rsquo;ll deal with why.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on Prayer</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/thoughts-on-prayer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/thoughts-on-prayer/</guid><description>In studying prayer recently, I have a few more thoughts that did not find a home among the other writings on prayer. I have captured them below in no particular order other than the sequence in which they were brought to mind.
Pray for Your Enemies Let us not forget that we are called to &amp;ldquo;love your enemies and pray for those who persecute you&amp;rdquo; (Matthew 5:44). Notice a couple of things here.</description></item></channel></rss>