<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Truth on Bible Research</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/truth/</link><description>Recent content in Truth on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/truth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Truth and Validity in Hermeneutics</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/truth-and-validity-of-hermeneutics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/truth-and-validity-of-hermeneutics/</guid><description>Disclaimer What I present here is a nascent concept and one that has probably already been articulated. If you have any feedback or know of someone who has already introduced a concept like the one below, please let me know. Thanks!
Abstract Part of the confusion about hermeneutics, especially in the world of conservative evangelicalism, is a failure to differentiate between the truth of a statement (whether the statement corresponds with objective reality) and the validity of a statement (whether the statement is actually found in the text).</description></item><item><title>Why I Cite Specific People, Books, and Sermons</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/disclaimer-for-citing-specific-examples/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/disclaimer-for-citing-specific-examples/</guid><description>Update (Summer 2020) In the past, I have cited specific examples (usually youtube clips) of issues and concerns I have with evangelicalism. I am no longer going to do this and have taken down mosts of my posts containing links to statements made by pastors. I do not object to the reasons for citing specific examples as detailed below and I see the merits of doing so, but I am unable to maintain a humble, gentle, peaceful heart when I cite specific examples, so I will no longer be doing so (at least not on a regular basis).</description></item></channel></rss>