<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Acts on Bible Research</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/tags/acts/</link><description>Recent content in Acts on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bible.hightower.space/tags/acts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Starting Point for Hermeneutics</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/starting-point-hermenuetics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/starting-point-hermenuetics/</guid><description>Definitions and Objectives Before jumping into the post, let me first define a couple of the phrases in the abstract.
&amp;ldquo;common-sense starting point&amp;rdquo; To clarify the objective of this blog post, I am not seeking to establish a complete and robust foundation for a hermeneutic. This is why I&amp;rsquo;m calling it a &amp;ldquo;common-sense starting point&amp;rdquo;; this blog post takes for granted many philosophical assumptions. While I do not deny defending my presuppositions would be a useful endeavor, I am not going to undertake it here.</description></item><item><title>Three Evidences that Baptism Is Not Necessary for Salvation</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/baptism-and-salvation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/baptism-and-salvation/</guid><description>There are some passages in scripture which appear, at first glance, to be saying that baptism is necessary for salvation (for example Mark 16:16, Acts 2:37-38, Galatians 3:27). In reformed, protestant circles, there are counter-arguments given for all of these passages (which I think are convincing and have sound Biblical grounds). I here present, however, three evidences from scripture that salvation does not require baptism. I would be curious how someone who believes that baptism is required for salvation would respond (you can contact me if you are such a person).</description></item></channel></rss>