<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Philosophy on Bible Research</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in Philosophy on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Truth and Validity in Hermeneutics</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/truth-and-validity-of-hermeneutics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/truth-and-validity-of-hermeneutics/</guid><description>Disclaimer What I present here is a nascent concept and one that has probably already been articulated. If you have any feedback or know of someone who has already introduced a concept like the one below, please let me know. Thanks!
Abstract Part of the confusion about hermeneutics, especially in the world of conservative evangelicalism, is a failure to differentiate between the truth of a statement (whether the statement corresponds with objective reality) and the validity of a statement (whether the statement is actually found in the text).</description></item><item><title>A Consequentialist Hermeneutic</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/consequentialist-hermeneutic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/consequentialist-hermeneutic/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Consequentialism, as its name suggests, is the view that normative properties depend only on consequences. This general approach can be applied at different levels to different normative properties of different kinds of things&amp;hellip;&amp;quot;1 A Consequentialist Hermeneutic Defining A Consequentialist Hermeneutic I believe that many conservative, evangelical churches today are comfortable with bad hermeneutics because because they suffer from &amp;ldquo;A Consequentialist Hermeneutic&amp;rdquo;. This disease is the attitude that any hermeneutic which leads to a true conclusion must be correct.</description></item><item><title>Why Christians Must be Wary of Pragmaticism</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/pragmaticism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/pragmaticism/</guid><description>Pragmaticism What is Pragmaticism? Pragmaticism1is a methodology for &amp;ldquo;reaching a clearness of thought of a far higher grade than the &amp;lsquo;distinctness&amp;rsquo; of the logicians&amp;rdquo;2. It makes a number of ontological claims such as:
&amp;ldquo;Our idea of anything is our idea of its sensible effects; and if we fancy that we have any other we deceive ourselves, and mistake a mere sensation accompanying the thought for a part of the thought itself.</description></item><item><title>What Is the Psychosomatic Unity?</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/psychosomatic-unity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/psychosomatic-unity/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Instead of a transcendent excursion into an altered consciousness, sensory deprivation had hilariously underscored the primacy of my body; it was almost a purely physical experience from start to finish. It was like being at a meditation retreat with a runny nose. My brain was simply incapable of escaping the signals my body was sending it&amp;hellip; Don’t get me wrong. I’m a neuroscience junkie. But we are not just a brain in a jar; we are also bodies, and what we do with those bodies can influence the brain.</description></item><item><title>What Is a Human Being?</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/what-is-a-human-being/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/what-is-a-human-being/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Let Us make man in Our image, according to Our likeness; and let them rule over the fish of the sea and over the birds of the sky and over the cattle and over all the earth, and over every creeping thing that creeps on the earth. God created man in His own image, in the image of God He created him; male and female He created them.&amp;quot;1 &amp;ldquo;What is man that You magnify him, and the You set Your heart on him&amp;hellip;&amp;quot;2 &amp;ldquo;To properly understand man, one must do so from a God-centered perspective.</description></item></channel></rss>