<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Holiness on Bible Research</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/tags/holiness/</link><description>Recent content in Holiness on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 06:21:22 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bible.hightower.space/tags/holiness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why Every Christian Must Fight and Flee Pornography</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/why-stop-watching-pornography/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/why-stop-watching-pornography/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s cut to the chase&amp;hellip; pornography has been cited as an epidemic of our age.1It is ubiquitous and easily accessible. There is a lot which can be said on the subject from many different angles and different perspectives, but for now, I&amp;rsquo;m going to present four motives that should animate every Christian to fight and flee pornography. I hope to discuss how to fight and flee pornography at some point, but for now, we&amp;rsquo;ll deal with why.</description></item><item><title>Psalm 90: The Problem of God's Immanence</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/sovereign-and-immanent-god/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/sovereign-and-immanent-god/</guid><description>Before we begin, let&amp;rsquo;s define some of the terms with which we may not be familiar:
Sovereignty of God: God&amp;rsquo;s absolute control and rule over everything.
Immanence of God: The tendency of God to relate with His creation and interact in human history.
If both of these attributes, as well as Holiness and Omniscience, are accurate descriptions of God&amp;rsquo;s character (and they are according to the testimony of Psalm 90 and scripture as a whole), then humans have a big problem; A God who is sovereign (in control), omniscient (knows everything a man does, thinks and feels), holy (separated and opposed to evil), and immanent (He relates with His creation) will produce a conundrum where God interacts and relates with His creation (due to His immanence) while killing them for their sin (because of His omniscience, sovereignty, and holiness).</description></item></channel></rss>