<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Galatians on Bible Research</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/tags/galatians/</link><description>Recent content in Galatians on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bible.hightower.space/tags/galatians/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Starting Point for Hermeneutics</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/starting-point-hermenuetics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/starting-point-hermenuetics/</guid><description>Definitions and Objectives Before jumping into the post, let me first define a couple of the phrases in the abstract.
&amp;ldquo;common-sense starting point&amp;rdquo; To clarify the objective of this blog post, I am not seeking to establish a complete and robust foundation for a hermeneutic. This is why I&amp;rsquo;m calling it a &amp;ldquo;common-sense starting point&amp;rdquo;; this blog post takes for granted many philosophical assumptions. While I do not deny defending my presuppositions would be a useful endeavor, I am not going to undertake it here.</description></item><item><title>Fighting Sin by Serving</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/fight-sin-by-serving/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/fight-sin-by-serving/</guid><description>I was reading Galatians 5:13 recently and this jumped out at me:
For you were called to freedom, brethren; only do not turn your freedom into an opportunity for the flesh, but through love serve one another.
In our efforts to glorify God and fight sin, one helpful strategy that I pull from this verse is to be busy serving one another. This has the dual benefits of keeping you busy and focusing your efforts on serving Christ and His church.</description></item><item><title>If you can read this... Thank a Teacher!</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/thank-your-teachers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/thank-your-teachers/</guid><description>All it takes is a quick email, phone call, or even a text. Or better yet&amp;hellip; next time you see them, take some time to let them know how much you appreciate what they do for you. It is really hard to be a teacher and is often a thank-less endeavour which can get depressing over time. Even a short word of thanks can go great lengths to encourage your teacher.</description></item></channel></rss>