<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prayer on Bible Research</title>
    <link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/prayer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prayer on Bible Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 05:21:22 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/prayer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Prayer?</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/what-is-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 05:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/what-is-prayer/</guid>
      <description>What is Prayer? The most basic and robust definition I can muster is:
 Prayer is talking to God.
 I would like to break this phrase down to better explain myself. Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the phrase &amp;ldquo;talking to&amp;rdquo;.
The phrase &amp;ldquo;talking to&amp;rdquo; is important for at least two reasons. First, prayer in the Bible is often done by speaking out loud to God. For example, Jesus in John 17:1 &amp;ldquo;spoke these things; and lifting up His eyes to heaven, He said&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (emphasis added).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer Plan</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/prayer-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/prayer-plan/</guid>
      <description>I use it as a system for guiding my prayer life and I hope you find it helpful. Feel free to tweak and modify it as you see fit.
Basics There are two basic parts of this system:
 Prayer items Bible passages  The idea is that you split up your prayer items over a week and will have a specific Bible passage to guide your prayer each week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Spiritual Disciplines: Prayer</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-prayer/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a series called Practical Spiritual Disciplines in which I will be discussing how to practice the spiritual disciplines.
 Since [prayer] is a duty of such absolute necessity for all and of such universal use, it is fitting we should all know how to perform it aright, that it may be accepted by the great God, and become a delightful and profitable exercise to our own souls and to those that join with us.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>