<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prayer on Bible Research</title>
    <link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/prayer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prayer on Bible Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/prayer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Prayer</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/thoughts-on-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/thoughts-on-prayer/</guid>
      <description>In studying prayer recently, I have a few more thoughts that did not find a home among the other writings on prayer. I have captured them below in no particular order other than the sequence in which they were brought to mind.
Pray for Your Enemies Let us not forget that we are called to &amp;ldquo;love your enemies and pray for those who persecute you&amp;rdquo; (Matthew 5:44). Notice a couple of things here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Should We Pray?</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/why-pray/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 05:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/why-pray/</guid>
      <description>Reasons to Pray Scripture gives numerous reasons why we should pray. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at a few examples. I&amp;rsquo;m going to split the reasons why we should pray into two categories:
We should pray in order to:
 Glorify God Enjoy Him forever  This way of breaking these reasons down is based on the first question and answer of the Westminster Confession of Faith.
&amp;ldquo;to glorify God&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; We should pray because prayer glorifies God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Prayer?</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/what-is-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 05:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/what-is-prayer/</guid>
      <description>[P]rayer is a retirement from earth and a retreat from our fellow creatures to fix our attention on God and communicate with Him who dwells in heaven.
~ Isaac Watts - A Guide to Prayer
 What is Prayer? The most basic and robust definition I can think of is:
 Prayer is talking to God.1
 I would like to break this phrase down to better explain myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer Plan</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/prayer-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/prayer-plan/</guid>
      <description>I use it as a system for guiding my prayer life and I hope you find it helpful. Feel free to modify it as you see fit.
Basics There are two basic parts of this system:
 Prayer items Bible passages  The idea is that you split up your prayer items over a week and will have a specific Bible passage to guide your prayer each week. For example, let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a friend named Martha and you want to pray for her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Spiritual Disciplines: Prayer</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-prayer/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a series called Practical Spiritual Disciplines in which I will be discussing how to practice the spiritual disciplines.
 Since [prayer] is a duty of such absolute necessity for all and of such universal use, it is fitting we should all know how to perform it aright, that it may be accepted by the great God, and become a delightful and profitable exercise to our own souls and to those that join with us.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>