<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Prayer on Bible Research</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/prayer/</link><description>Recent content in Prayer on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/prayer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>God's Attributes Make Prayer Possible</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/gods-attributes-and-prayer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/gods-attributes-and-prayer/</guid><description>Many definitions of prayer boil down to something like: &amp;ldquo;Talking to God&amp;rdquo;. I love this definition. The focus and emphasis, however, is often placed on the &amp;ldquo;talking&amp;rdquo; (i.e. our action in prayer). Certainly, this is important, but we must also recognize that it is the God to whom we are praying that separates our prayers from the prayers of Muslims, Hindus, and Mormons. People of many religions pray. What fundamentally differentiates Christian prayer from prayer in other religions is the character and nature of the God of the Bible.</description></item><item><title>Why Pray Using the Bible</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/why-pray-the-bible/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/why-pray-the-bible/</guid><description>As I describe here, my prayer life used to be pitiful. My prayers where repetitive, virtually meaningless and unguided ramblings that God would &amp;ldquo;be with&amp;rdquo; someone (whatever that means). It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until I heard a sermon on using the Bible to guide our prayers that I was able to significantly change the way I pray.
In this sermon, the pastor argued that we should use a passage of scripture to guide our prayers.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts On Prayerlessness</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/excuses-for-prayerlessness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/excuses-for-prayerlessness/</guid><description>My Excuses When it comes to my excuses for not praying, I have three, solid pleas which I regret to admit have often freed me from the bond of love and intimacy with God:
&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m too busy.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m working on things which are more important than prayer.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t need to pray right now.&amp;rdquo; (i.e. &amp;ldquo;My relationship with God is ok right now and I don&amp;rsquo;t need to spend time with Him.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on Prayer</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/thoughts-on-prayer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/thoughts-on-prayer/</guid><description>In studying prayer recently, I have a few more thoughts that did not find a home among the other writings on prayer. I have captured them below in no particular order other than the sequence in which they were brought to mind.
Pray for Your Enemies Let us not forget that we are called to &amp;ldquo;love your enemies and pray for those who persecute you&amp;rdquo; (Matthew 5:44). Notice a couple of things here.</description></item><item><title>Why Should We Pray?</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/why-pray/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 05:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/why-pray/</guid><description>Reasons to Pray Scripture gives numerous reasons why we should pray. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at a few examples. I&amp;rsquo;m going to split the reasons why we should pray into two categories:
We should pray in order to:
Glorify God Enjoy Him forever This way of breaking these reasons down is based on the first question and answer of the Westminster Confession of Faith.
&amp;ldquo;to glorify God&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; We should pray because prayer glorifies God.</description></item><item><title>What Is Prayer?</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/what-is-prayer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 05:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/what-is-prayer/</guid><description>[P]rayer is a retirement from earth and a retreat from our fellow creatures to fix our attention on God and communicate with Him who dwells in heaven.
~ Isaac Watts - A Guide to Prayer
What is Prayer? The most basic and robust definition I can think of is:
Prayer is talking to God.1 I would like to break this phrase down to better explain myself. Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the phrase &amp;ldquo;talking to&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>A Prayer Plan for Making Prayer a Habit</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/prayer-plan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/prayer-plan/</guid><description>Why? Let me begin by explaining why I developed this plan. If I&amp;rsquo;m honest, my prayer time was embarrassing. I told people I would pray for them only to pray for them once and promptly forget about them entirely. When I was praying, I was constantly fighting a wandering mind and sleep-inducing boredom as I would use the same phrases over-and-over:
&amp;ldquo;God, please be with Martha in her life.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Practical Spiritual Disciplines: Prayer</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-prayer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-prayer/</guid><description>This is part of a series called Practical Spiritual Disciplines in which I will be discussing how to practice the spiritual disciplines.
Since [prayer] is a duty of such absolute necessity for all and of such universal use, it is fitting we should all know how to perform it aright, that it may be accepted by the great God, and become a delightful and profitable exercise to our own souls and to those that join with us.</description></item></channel></rss>