<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Psalms on Bible Research</title>
    <link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/psalms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Psalms on Bible Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 06:21:22 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/psalms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 62: God&#39;s Unique Ability to Save, Satisfy, and Sustain</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/psalm-62/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/psalm-62/</guid>
      <description>Background According to the superscription, Psalm 62 is a psalm of David. While there is no explicit, historical context for the psalm, it refers to those who &amp;ldquo;assail a man that you may murder him&amp;rdquo; (Psalm 62:3). There were multiple points in David&amp;rsquo;s life when people were seeking to kill him, so this psalm could have been inspired by many of the events in David&amp;rsquo;s life.
Structure The psalm breaks down into five sections:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 90: The Problem of God&#39;s Immanence</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/sovereign-and-immanent-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/sovereign-and-immanent-god/</guid>
      <description>Before we begin, let&amp;rsquo;s define some of the terms with which we may not be familiar:
 Sovereignty of God: God&amp;rsquo;s absolute control and rule over everything.
Immanence of God: The tendency of God to relate with His creation and interact in human history.
 If both of these attributes, as well as Holiness and Omniscience, are accurate descriptions of God&amp;rsquo;s character (and they are according to the testimony of Psalm 90 and scripture as a whole), then humans have a big problem; A God who is sovereign (in control), omniscient (knows everything a man does, thinks and feels), holy (separated and opposed to evil), and immanent (He relates with His creation) will produce a conundrum where God interacts and relates with His creation (due to His immanence) while killing them for their sin (because of His omniscience, sovereignty, and holiness).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>