<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Bible Research</title>
    <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Bible Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Prayer</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/thoughts-on-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/thoughts-on-prayer/</guid>
      <description>In studying prayer recently, I have a few more thoughts that did not find a home among the other writings on prayer. I have captured them below in no particular order other than the sequence in which they were brought to mind.
Pray for Your Enemies Let us not forget that we are called to &amp;ldquo;love your enemies and pray for those who persecute you&amp;rdquo; (Matthew 5:44). Notice a couple of things here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Should We Pray?</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/why-pray/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 05:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/why-pray/</guid>
      <description>Reasons to Pray Scripture gives numerous reasons why we should pray. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at a few examples. I&amp;rsquo;m going to split the reasons why we should pray into two categories:
We should pray in order to:
 Glorify God Enjoy Him forever  This way of breaking these reasons down is based on the first question and answer of the Westminster Confession of Faith.
&amp;ldquo;to glorify God&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; We should pray because prayer glorifies God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Prayer?</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/what-is-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 05:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/what-is-prayer/</guid>
      <description>[P]rayer is a retirement from earth and a retreat from our fellow creatures to fix our attention on God and communicate with Him who dwells in heaven.
~ Isaac Watts - A Guide to Prayer
 What is Prayer? The most basic and robust definition I can think of is:
 Prayer is talking to God.1
 I would like to break this phrase down to better explain myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prayer Plan</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/prayer-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/prayer-plan/</guid>
      <description>I use it as a system for guiding my prayer life and I hope you find it helpful. Feel free to modify it as you see fit.
Basics There are two basic parts of this system:
 Prayer items Bible passages  The idea is that you split up your prayer items over a week and will have a specific Bible passage to guide your prayer each week. For example, let&amp;rsquo;s say you have a friend named Martha and you want to pray for her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Spiritual Disciplines: Prayer</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-prayer/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a series called Practical Spiritual Disciplines in which I will be discussing how to practice the spiritual disciplines.
 Since [prayer] is a duty of such absolute necessity for all and of such universal use, it is fitting we should all know how to perform it aright, that it may be accepted by the great God, and become a delightful and profitable exercise to our own souls and to those that join with us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Spiritual Disciplines: What are Spiritual Disciplines?</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-what/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-what/</guid>
      <description>This is part of a series called Practical Spiritual Disciplines which is designed to show you what tools and activities God has given us to grow and how we can practices these disciplines in our daily lives.
 “We are far too easily pleased.”
~ C.S. Lewis, The Weight of Glory
 Definition A spiritual discipline is an activity, which ought to be a habit, that the Bible prescribes for Christians to help them grow spiritually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Spiritual Disciplines: Introduction</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/practical-spiritual-disciplines-why/</guid>
      <description>Motivation In Western, conservative Churches, our knowledge often far exceeds our living. That is, we usually know far more about theology than we live out in our lives. When it comes down to it, most of us know what we are supposed to do (for example: pray, read your Bible, evangelize, etc.) and why we are supposed to do those things, but we still are not doing the things we should.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Performative Nature of Wisdom Literature</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/performative-wisdom-lit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/performative-wisdom-lit/</guid>
      <description>Performative Wisdom Literature In linguistics, performativity describes of the ability of communication (in any form) to do something.1 This is a break from the way we normally view language as a means of describing something or asking someone to do something. Language itself can do things. For example, saying &amp;ldquo;I now pronounce you husband and wife&amp;rdquo; in the proper context is not just a declarative statement about what I happen to be doing at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 62: God&#39;s Unique Ability to Save, Satisfy, and Sustain</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/psalm-62/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/psalm-62/</guid>
      <description>Background According to the superscription, Psalm 62 is a psalm of David. While there is no explicit, historical context for the psalm, it refers to those who &amp;ldquo;assail a man that you may murder him&amp;rdquo; (Psalm 62:3). There were multiple points in David&amp;rsquo;s life when people were seeking to kill him, so this psalm could have been inspired by many of the events in David&amp;rsquo;s life.
Structure The psalm breaks down into five sections:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If you can read this... Thank a Teacher!</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/thank-your-teachers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/thank-your-teachers/</guid>
      <description>All it takes is a quick email, phone call, or even a text. Or better yet&amp;hellip; next time you see them, take some time to let them know how much you appreciate what they do for you. It is really hard to be a teacher and is often a thank-less endeavour which can get depressing over time. Even a short word of thanks can go great lengths to encourage your teacher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cain &amp; Abel</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/cain-and-abel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/cain-and-abel/</guid>
      <description>Genesis 4:1-15 describes the infamous story of Cain and Abel. In this story, two brothers, Cain (a &amp;ldquo;tiller of the ground&amp;rdquo;) and Abel (a &amp;ldquo;keeper of flocks&amp;rdquo;), bring a sacrifice before God (see Genesis 4:2-3). Verses three and four tell us that Cain brings &amp;ldquo;an offering of the fruit of the ground&amp;rdquo; and Abel brings &amp;ldquo;the firstlings of his flock and their fat portions&amp;rdquo;. The end of verse four and beginning of verse five reads: &amp;ldquo;And the LORD had regard for Abel and for his offering; but for Cain and for his offering He had no regard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 90: The Problem of God&#39;s Immanence</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/sovereign-and-immanent-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/sovereign-and-immanent-god/</guid>
      <description>Before we begin, let&amp;rsquo;s define some of the terms with which we may not be familiar:
 Sovereignty of God: God&amp;rsquo;s absolute control and rule over everything.
Immanence of God: The tendency of God to relate with His creation and interact in human history.
 If both of these attributes, as well as Holiness and Omniscience, are accurate descriptions of God&amp;rsquo;s character (and they are according to the testimony of Psalm 90 and scripture as a whole), then humans have a big problem; A God who is sovereign (in control), omniscient (knows everything a man does, thinks and feels), holy (separated and opposed to evil), and immanent (He relates with His creation) will produce a conundrum where God interacts and relates with His creation (due to His immanence) while killing them for their sin (because of His omniscience, sovereignty, and holiness).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spies&#39; Bad Report</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/spies-bad-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/spies-bad-report/</guid>
      <description>What is described below is, in my estimation, a well-supported conjecture, but a conjecture nonetheless. Consider it thoughtfully and critically.
I believe that Numbers 13:25-33 can be broken down as follows:
 Numbers 13:25-26 - General summary of events. Spies return and give their report. Numbers 13:27-29 - This is said by the spies (particularly the ten spies who did not believe God) privately to Moses (at least not in the hearing of the people before Moses).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Audacity of Man-made Religion</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/the-audacity-of-manmade-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/the-audacity-of-manmade-religion/</guid>
      <description>One of the clear themes throughout the Bible is that it is God who defines how His creation must/should interact with Him. We are in no position (that is, we have no authority) to come to God on our own terms. If there is a God that is anything like the one described in the Bible, He has the inherit right, authority, and power to demand how we should relate to Him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you are Apathetic Toward Leviticus.</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/leviticus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/leviticus/</guid>
      <description>Mistakes We often make two, critical mistakes when we read the book of Leviticus. First, we are to busy looking for imperatives and applications that we miss the meaning (and, therefore, the real applications). Second, we isolate Leviticus and don&amp;rsquo;t read it as part of a larger story. Let us begin with the first issue.
We, Christians who hold the Bible as the sole authority for life and Godliness, must stop reading the Bible selfishly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Relationships between the Five &#39;Solas&#39; of the Reformation.</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/five-solae/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/five-solae/</guid>
      <description>The principles behind the reformation are often summarized in five exclusive statements deemed &amp;lsquo;Solae&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Solas&amp;rsquo;:
 Sola Scriptura (&amp;ldquo;Scripture alone&amp;rdquo;) Sola Fide (&amp;ldquo;faith alone&amp;rdquo;) Sola Gratia (&amp;ldquo;grace alone&amp;rdquo;) Solus Christus (&amp;ldquo;Christ alone&amp;rdquo;) Soli Deo gloria (&amp;ldquo;glory to God alone&amp;rdquo;)  These statements have been used both to describe what Luther and the other reformers believed as well as to discern what the Bible does and does not teach. Because we often see the five solas listed out in bullet points, we often do not consider the relationships between them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passages for a Preliminary Understanding of the Plagues and the Exodus</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/israel-in-egypt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/israel-in-egypt/</guid>
      <description>When we think about Israel&amp;rsquo;s time in Egypt, the plagues, and Israel&amp;rsquo;s Exodus from Egypt, there are a few passages that are important to keep in mind.
 Genesis 15:13-16 - Israel&amp;rsquo;s slavery in Egypt is promised as well as God&amp;rsquo;s judgement on Egypt and Israel&amp;rsquo;s subsequent possessions. Genesis 50:25-26 (and Exodus 23:19) - Joseph asks, with faith in God&amp;rsquo;s promise, that his bones be taken out of Egypt and buried in the land promised to Israel by God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is Canaan Cursed Rather than Ham?</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/canaan-and-ham/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/canaan-and-ham/</guid>
      <description>The text does not give us enough details to know exactly why, but I think there are a few things we can conclude from the passage:
 Part of the reason some readers take issue with this passage is that they think Ham is getting off without punishment for his offense. The punishment that fell to Canaan, however, would have felt like a punishment to Ham as well. His line was not blessed and one of his sons was cursed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watch your Lingo!</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/watch-your-lingo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/watch-your-lingo/</guid>
      <description>Language is critically important as it is the medium through which ideas are communicated. Unfortunately, I am noticing that many Christians are alienating themselves from secular culture simply because they are using Christian jargon which has little to no meaning outside of a Christian community. In this blog post, I highlight a few examples and suggest some of the dangers that can arise if we are not aware and cautious about our jargon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Satan or Serpent? Understanding the Protevangelium.</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/defending-protevangelium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/defending-protevangelium/</guid>
      <description>I was recently reading through Genesis and paused when I got to Genesis 3:14-15. I have always been taught that Genesis 3:15 was directed not at the physical serpent (that is, the creature itself), but the spiritual &amp;lsquo;serpent&amp;rsquo; (who is Satan). But in my recent reading, I asked myself: Are we right to interpret Genesis 3:15 in this way? This post contains my conclusion on the subject after thought and investigation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please Pass the Pomegranate. Understanding the Nature of Sin in Genesis 3.</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/understanding-sin-from-genesis3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/understanding-sin-from-genesis3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The Devil Made Me Do It&amp;rdquo;? First, consider who or what was involved in making Eve sin. One of the answers is clearly Satan in the form of the serpent (see Genesis 3:1). It is Satan who asks the infamous question &amp;ldquo;Hath God said&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; and causes Eve to doubt the words of God. It is important to recognize, however, that Satan is not the only thing that drives Eve to sin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Objectives</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/blog-objectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/blog-objectives/</guid>
      <description>The basic objective of this blog is to give me a platform to communicate some of the thoughts and observations I have that don&amp;rsquo;t fit well into the Bible Notes project. My goal in voicing some of these thoughts is to provide more resources that will strengthen the Church and produce mature, thoughtful followers of Christ. It also gives me the chance to hone my writing and communication skills (which I then hope to use to strengthen the Church).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>