<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pragmaticism on Bible Research</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/pragmaticism/</link><description>Recent content in Pragmaticism on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/pragmaticism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Be Careful How you Define the Gospel</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/defining-gospel/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/defining-gospel/</guid><description>The Danger When defining the Gospel, I often hear people conflate a correct response to the Gospel or the effects of the Gospel with the content of the Gospel itself. This is dangerous and inaccurate for (at least) two reasons:
It confuses pragmatism and function with ontology (there is more on the danger of Pragmaticism here). It includes consequences in the definition rather than just the grounds. This breaks a basic principle of creating definitions, namely &amp;ldquo;that the attributes included in the definition should be always such as are the ground of the others rather than the consequences&amp;rdquo;1.</description></item><item><title>Why Christians Must be Wary of Pragmaticism</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/pragmaticism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/pragmaticism/</guid><description>Pragmaticism What is Pragmaticism? Pragmaticism1is a methodology for &amp;ldquo;reaching a clearness of thought of a far higher grade than the &amp;lsquo;distinctness&amp;rsquo; of the logicians&amp;rdquo;2. It makes a number of ontological claims such as:
&amp;ldquo;Our idea of anything is our idea of its sensible effects; and if we fancy that we have any other we deceive ourselves, and mistake a mere sensation accompanying the thought for a part of the thought itself.</description></item></channel></rss>