<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sovereignty on Bible Research</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/sovereignty/</link><description>Recent content in Sovereignty on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/sovereignty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Judge Not the Lord by Feeble Sense, but Trust Him for His Grace</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/judge-not-the-lord-by-feeble-sense/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/judge-not-the-lord-by-feeble-sense/</guid><description>God moves in a mysterious way His wonders to perform; He plants His footsteps in the sea, And rides upon the storm.
Deep in unfathomable mines Of never-failing skill He treasures up His bright designs, And works His sovereign will.
Ye fearful saints, fresh courage take, The clouds ye so much dread Are big with mercy, and shall break In blessings on your head.
Judge not the Lord by feeble sense, But trust Him for His grace; Behind a frowning providence He hides a smiling face.</description></item><item><title>What Is Prayer?</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/what-is-prayer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 05:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/what-is-prayer/</guid><description>[P]rayer is a retirement from earth and a retreat from our fellow creatures to fix our attention on God and communicate with Him who dwells in heaven.
~ Isaac Watts - A Guide to Prayer
What is Prayer? The most basic and robust definition I can think of is:
Prayer is talking to God.1 I would like to break this phrase down to better explain myself. Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the phrase &amp;ldquo;talking to&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Psalm 90: The Problem of God's Immanence</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/sovereign-and-immanent-god/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/sovereign-and-immanent-god/</guid><description>Before we begin, let&amp;rsquo;s define some of the terms with which we may not be familiar:
Sovereignty of God: God&amp;rsquo;s absolute control and rule over everything.
Immanence of God: The tendency of God to relate with His creation and interact in human history.
If both of these attributes, as well as Holiness and Omniscience, are accurate descriptions of God&amp;rsquo;s character (and they are according to the testimony of Psalm 90 and scripture as a whole), then humans have a big problem; A God who is sovereign (in control), omniscient (knows everything a man does, thinks and feels), holy (separated and opposed to evil), and immanent (He relates with His creation) will produce a conundrum where God interacts and relates with His creation (due to His immanence) while killing them for their sin (because of His omniscience, sovereignty, and holiness).</description></item></channel></rss>