<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Christian Worldview on Bible Research</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/christian-worldview/</link><description>Recent content in Christian Worldview on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 06:21:22 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/christian-worldview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Is the Psychosomatic Unity?</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/psychosomatic-unity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/psychosomatic-unity/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Instead of a transcendent excursion into an altered consciousness, sensory deprivation had hilariously underscored the primacy of my body; it was almost a purely physical experience from start to finish. It was like being at a meditation retreat with a runny nose. My brain was simply incapable of escaping the signals my body was sending it&amp;hellip; Don’t get me wrong. I’m a neuroscience junkie. But we are not just a brain in a jar; we are also bodies, and what we do with those bodies can influence the brain.</description></item><item><title>What Is a Human Being?</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/what-is-a-human-being/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/what-is-a-human-being/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Let Us make man in Our image, according to Our likeness; and let them rule over the fish of the sea and over the birds of the sky and over the cattle and over all the earth, and over every creeping thing that creeps on the earth. God created man in His own image, in the image of God He created him; male and female He created them.&amp;quot;1 &amp;ldquo;What is man that You magnify him, and the You set Your heart on him&amp;hellip;&amp;quot;2 &amp;ldquo;To properly understand man, one must do so from a God-centered perspective.</description></item></channel></rss>