<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thought on Bible Research</title>
    <link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/thought/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thought on Bible Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 06:21:22 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/thought/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Performative Nature of Wisdom Literature</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/performative-wisdom-lit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/performative-wisdom-lit/</guid>
      <description>Wisdom literature in the Bible (books like Job, Proverbs, and Ecclesiastes) is not easy to understand&amp;hellip; and this is no accident. It is designed not only to show you what true wisdom is, but also to produce it within you. This is what makes wisdom literature performative.
In linguistics, performativity describes of the ability of communication (in any form) to do something.1 This is a break from the way we normally view language as a means of describing something or asking someone to do something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 62: God&#39;s Unique Ability to Save, Satisfy, and Sustain</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/psalm-62/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/psalm-62/</guid>
      <description>The record of human history demonstrates that God does three, wonderful things for mankind: He saves; He satisfies; He sustains. Psalm 62 celebrates these wonderful truths and emphasizes God&amp;rsquo;s unique ability to provide in each area.
Background According to the superscription, Psalm 62 is a psalm of David. While there is no explicit, historical context for the psalm, it refers to those who &amp;ldquo;assail a man that you may murder him&amp;rdquo; (Psalm 62:3).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psalm 90: The Problem of God&#39;s Immanence</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/sovereign-and-immanent-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/sovereign-and-immanent-god/</guid>
      <description>Psalm 90 deals with one of the most basic challenges facing humanity: If there really is a sovereign, holy God who created everything and knows our every thought but is also immanent, how can man live and find meaning in living?
Before we begin, let&amp;rsquo;s define some of the terms with which we may not be familiar:
 Sovereignty of God: God&amp;rsquo;s absolute control and rule over everything.
Immanence of God: The tendency of God to relate with His creation and interact in human history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spies&#39; Bad Report</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/spies-bad-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/spies-bad-report/</guid>
      <description>In Numbers 13:25-33, the spies sent into the Promised Land return with a scouting report. There is some subtlety, however, to the way in which the report is described in the text that leads me to believe there is more to this account than is normally assumed. This post lays out what I believe to be the best understanding of the passage.
What is described below is, in my estimation, a well-supported theory, but a theory nonetheless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Audacity of Man-made Religion</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/the-audacity-of-manmade-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/the-audacity-of-manmade-religion/</guid>
      <description>Man-made religion is futile and abhorrent for a few reasons, but one, particular horror towers above the rest. Behind man-made religion is the arrogant declaration that we define the terms of our relationship with God. Thus, it is impossible for man-made religions to worship anything but man himself.
One of the clear themes throughout the Bible is that it is God who defines how His creation must/should interact with Him. We are in no position (that is, we have no authority) to come to God on our own terms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you are apathetic toward Leviticus.</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/leviticus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/leviticus/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s face it, Leviticus can be a hard book to read. It is probably the biggest killers of Bible reading plans. How can we get any value out of this book? In this post, I point out a couple mistakes we make when come to the book of Leviticus and suggest some ways to better understand and apply Leviticus.
Mistakes We often make two, critical mistakes when we read the book of Leviticus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Relationships between the Five &#39;Solas&#39; of the Reformation.</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/five-solae/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/five-solae/</guid>
      <description>Many protestants are very familiar with the five &amp;lsquo;solas&amp;rsquo; of the Reformation, but do you understand how they relate with one another?
The principles behind the reformation are often summarized in five exclusive statements deemed &amp;lsquo;Solae&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Solas&amp;rsquo;:
 Sola Scriptura (&amp;ldquo;Scripture alone&amp;rdquo;) Sola Fide (&amp;ldquo;faith alone&amp;rdquo;) Sola Gratia (&amp;ldquo;grace alone&amp;rdquo;) Solus Christus (&amp;ldquo;Christ alone&amp;rdquo;) Soli Deo gloria (&amp;ldquo;glory to God alone&amp;rdquo;)  These statements have been used both to describe what Luther and the other reformers believed as well as to discern what the Bible does and does not teach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please Pass the Pomegranate. Understanding the Nature of Sin in Genesis 3.</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/understanding-sin-from-genesis3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/understanding-sin-from-genesis3/</guid>
      <description>Just three short chapters into the narrative of God&amp;rsquo;s redemptive plan, we find Adam and Eve in the Garden of Eden, clothed with fig leaves and damning themselves and their children to a life separated from God. There are two observations about the story in Genesis 3 that I wish to make which will help us better understand the nature of sin.
First, consider who or what was involved in making Eve sin.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>