<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thought on Bible Research</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/tags/thought/</link><description>Recent content in Thought on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bible.hightower.space/tags/thought/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Structure of Deuteronomy (part 1)</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/structure-deuteronomy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/structure-deuteronomy/</guid><description>Introduction This blog post presents the argument that Deuteronomy is an exposition of the Ten Commandments. I present the central argument followed by supporting evidence.
Deuteronomy as an Exposition of the Ten Commandments For most of Christian history, there has been discussion and debate about how Christians ought to make sense of the books of the Law. The central section of Deuteronomy (chapters 12 - 26), for example, has raised questions like: &amp;ldquo;Is there any order to these rules?</description></item><item><title>Jesus' Words on Forgiveness (Part 1 - Book of Matthew)</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/jesus-on-forgiveness-matthew/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/jesus-on-forgiveness-matthew/</guid><description>Preface I have two goals for you, my reader, in this post:
I would like to challenge you with Jesus' words on forgiveness. Jesus is not flippant or trivial on the topic of forgiveness and he attributes a weight and significance to forgiveness that is, I think, often lessened. I hope you will consider the practical implications of Jesus' words for your own life. In the words of Paul: Let all bitterness and wrath and anger and clamor and slander be put away from you, along with all malice.</description></item><item><title>False Grounds for Assurance of Salvation (part 1)</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/false-grounds-for-assurance-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/false-grounds-for-assurance-1/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Oh listen, do you love the Word of God? There&amp;rsquo;s no greater proof that you have really passed from death unto life than if you have an insatiable love for the Word of God.&amp;quot;1 Preface A Warning Before continuing, I encourage you to read the warning here.
If you are looking for the grounds of assurance of salvation (the means by which we can know that we are saved), I don&amp;rsquo;t have any to offer you right now and sincerely ask that you stop reading.</description></item><item><title>A 2020 Warning</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/2020-warning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/2020-warning/</guid><description>The following points have been adapted from my post seeking to prove that Martin Luther taught a false paradigm of salvation.
A Warning If you read any articles on my blog, you should know a number of things.
First, I&amp;rsquo;m confused. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for what the Bible says about how sinful man can be reconciled to a Holy God, this is not a blog that will answer that question (at least not right now) and I sincerely ask you to stop reading.</description></item><item><title>On Spiritual Regrowth and New Year's Resolutions</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/do-something/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/do-something/</guid><description>A new year begins and my life is busier than ever before. I now have less time to study Scripture and have more responsibilities outside of the realm of scriptural and theological studies. I used to be able to study Scripture and wrestle with theological questions for hours and hours, but now have half the time, at best, that I used to have. When I studied for long hours, I enjoyed learning about God from His word and felt closer to God, even though my studies raised a number of profound theological and philosophical questions.</description></item><item><title>A Deadly Lifestyle (part 2): How I Feel About Church and the Bible Right Now</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/deadly-lifestyle-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/deadly-lifestyle-part-2/</guid><description>This is a follow up to the first &amp;ldquo;Deadly Lifestyle&amp;rdquo; post.
The Situation It is very difficult for me to read/study the Bible right now. Here is what happens almost every time I open the Bible:
I pray As you will see below, I really need help! I start reading for example, I recently read Acts 8 I notice something fascinating/interesting In Acts 8, it is interesting that Simon the Magician is said to have &amp;ldquo;believed&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;being baptized, he continued on with Philip&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (Acts 8:13) and yet Peter harshly rebukes him for trying to buy the free gift of God and calls him to repent (Acts 8:21-23).</description></item><item><title>A Deadly Lifestyle: How I Feel About Church and the Bible Right Now</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/deadly-lifestyle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/deadly-lifestyle/</guid><description>For the past year, going to church and reading the bible has felt like this:
I am shackled in a prison. I am periodically given enough &amp;lsquo;food&amp;rsquo; to live (I say &amp;lsquo;food&amp;rsquo; because some of it is inedible or undesirable (raw, rotting meat, bones, lard, etc.))&amp;hellip; but getting the food is difficult because the shackle on my neck has small protrusions or hooks on the inside designed to create small lacerations on my neck if I strain against the shackle too much.</description></item><item><title>God's Attributes Make Prayer Possible</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/gods-attributes-and-prayer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/gods-attributes-and-prayer/</guid><description>Many definitions of prayer boil down to something like: &amp;ldquo;Talking to God&amp;rdquo;. I love this definition. The focus and emphasis, however, is often placed on the &amp;ldquo;talking&amp;rdquo; (i.e. our action in prayer). Certainly, this is important, but we must also recognize that it is the God to whom we are praying that separates our prayers from the prayers of Muslims, Hindus, and Mormons. People of many religions pray. What fundamentally differentiates Christian prayer from prayer in other religions is the character and nature of the God of the Bible.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Temptation of Jesus in Light of Matthew 3:17</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/temptation-of-jesus-matthew/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/temptation-of-jesus-matthew/</guid><description>I recently heard a sermon on the temptation of Jesus (Matthew 4:1-11) in which the pastor said something that caught my attention, got me thinking, and led me to what I think is a deeper, richer understanding of this passage. While the pastor did not say what I am about to say explicitly, he hinted in its general direction and I am very grateful not just for this sermon, but also for his faithful ministry of the word of God.</description></item><item><title>Why I Use a Normal, Literal, and Grammatical Hermeneutic</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/why-literal-gramatical-hermenuetic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/why-literal-gramatical-hermenuetic/</guid><description>Definitions I believe that definitions and the meaning of words are important.1In the future, I intend to more thoroughly define and defend my hermeneutic (and define what I mean by &amp;lsquo;normal, literal, and grammatical&amp;rsquo;), but for now, I am just going to take for granted that my audience understands what I mean when I say &amp;ldquo;normal, literal, and grammatical hermeneutic&amp;rdquo;. For the rest of this blog post, I will use the acronym NLG to represent a normal, literal, and grammatical hermeneutic.</description></item><item><title>A Starting Point for Hermeneutics</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/starting-point-hermenuetics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/starting-point-hermenuetics/</guid><description>Definitions and Objectives Before jumping into the post, let me first define a couple of the phrases in the abstract.
&amp;ldquo;common-sense starting point&amp;rdquo; To clarify the objective of this blog post, I am not seeking to establish a complete and robust foundation for a hermeneutic. This is why I&amp;rsquo;m calling it a &amp;ldquo;common-sense starting point&amp;rdquo;; this blog post takes for granted many philosophical assumptions. While I do not deny defending my presuppositions would be a useful endeavor, I am not going to undertake it here.</description></item><item><title>Fighting Sin by Serving</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/fight-sin-by-serving/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/fight-sin-by-serving/</guid><description>I was reading Galatians 5:13 recently and this jumped out at me:
For you were called to freedom, brethren; only do not turn your freedom into an opportunity for the flesh, but through love serve one another.
In our efforts to glorify God and fight sin, one helpful strategy that I pull from this verse is to be busy serving one another. This has the dual benefits of keeping you busy and focusing your efforts on serving Christ and His church.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts On Prayerlessness</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/excuses-for-prayerlessness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/excuses-for-prayerlessness/</guid><description>My Excuses When it comes to my excuses for not praying, I have three, solid pleas which I regret to admit have often freed me from the bond of love and intimacy with God:
&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m too busy.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m working on things which are more important than prayer.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t need to pray right now.&amp;rdquo; (i.e. &amp;ldquo;My relationship with God is ok right now and I don&amp;rsquo;t need to spend time with Him.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on Prayer</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/thoughts-on-prayer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/thoughts-on-prayer/</guid><description>In studying prayer recently, I have a few more thoughts that did not find a home among the other writings on prayer. I have captured them below in no particular order other than the sequence in which they were brought to mind.
Pray for Your Enemies Let us not forget that we are called to &amp;ldquo;love your enemies and pray for those who persecute you&amp;rdquo; (Matthew 5:44). Notice a couple of things here.</description></item><item><title>The Performative Nature of Wisdom Literature</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/performative-wisdom-lit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/performative-wisdom-lit/</guid><description>Performative Wisdom Literature In linguistics, performativity describes of the ability of communication (in any form) to do something.1This is a break from the way we normally view language as a means of describing something or asking someone to do something. Language itself can do things. For example, saying &amp;ldquo;I now pronounce you husband and wife&amp;rdquo; in the proper context is not just a declarative statement about what I happen to be doing at the moment.</description></item><item><title>Psalm 62: God's Unique Ability to Save, Satisfy, and Sustain</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/psalm-62/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/psalm-62/</guid><description>Background According to the superscription, Psalm 62 is a psalm of David. While there is no explicit, historical context for the psalm, it refers to those who &amp;ldquo;assail a man that you may murder him&amp;rdquo; (Psalm 62:3). There were multiple points in David&amp;rsquo;s life when people were seeking to kill him, so this psalm could have been inspired by many of the events in David&amp;rsquo;s life.
Structure The psalm breaks down into five sections:</description></item><item><title>Psalm 90: The Problem of God's Immanence</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/sovereign-and-immanent-god/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/sovereign-and-immanent-god/</guid><description>Before we begin, let&amp;rsquo;s define some of the terms with which we may not be familiar:
Sovereignty of God: God&amp;rsquo;s absolute control and rule over everything.
Immanence of God: The tendency of God to relate with His creation and interact in human history.
If both of these attributes, as well as Holiness and Omniscience, are accurate descriptions of God&amp;rsquo;s character (and they are according to the testimony of Psalm 90 and scripture as a whole), then humans have a big problem; A God who is sovereign (in control), omniscient (knows everything a man does, thinks and feels), holy (separated and opposed to evil), and immanent (He relates with His creation) will produce a conundrum where God interacts and relates with His creation (due to His immanence) while killing them for their sin (because of His omniscience, sovereignty, and holiness).</description></item><item><title>The Spies' Bad Report</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/spies-bad-report/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/spies-bad-report/</guid><description>What is described below is, in my estimation, a well-supported conjecture, but a conjecture nonetheless. Consider it thoughtfully and critically.
I believe that Numbers 13:25-33 can be broken down as follows:
Numbers 13:25-26 - General summary of events. Spies return and give their report. Numbers 13:27-29 - This is said by the spies (particularly the ten spies who did not believe God) privately to Moses (at least not in the hearing of the people before Moses).</description></item><item><title>The Audacity of Man-made Religion</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/the-audacity-of-manmade-religion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/the-audacity-of-manmade-religion/</guid><description>One of the clear themes throughout the Bible is that it is God who defines how His creation must/should interact with Him. We are in no position (that is, we have no authority) to come to God on our own terms. If there is a God that is anything like the one described in the Bible, He has the inherit right, authority, and power to demand how we should relate to Him.</description></item><item><title>Why you are Apathetic Toward Leviticus</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/leviticus/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/leviticus/</guid><description>Mistakes We often make two, critical mistakes when we read the book of Leviticus. First, we are to busy looking for imperatives and applications that we miss the meaning (and, therefore, the real applications). Second, we isolate Leviticus and don&amp;rsquo;t read it as part of a larger story. Let us begin with the first issue.
We, Christians who hold the Bible as the sole authority for life and Godliness, must stop reading the Bible selfishly.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Relationships between the Five 'Solas' of the Reformation.</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/five-solae/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/five-solae/</guid><description>The principles behind the reformation are often summarized in five exclusive statements deemed &amp;lsquo;Solae&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Solas&amp;rsquo;:
Sola Scriptura (&amp;ldquo;Scripture alone&amp;rdquo;) Sola Fide (&amp;ldquo;faith alone&amp;rdquo;) Sola Gratia (&amp;ldquo;grace alone&amp;rdquo;) Solus Christus (&amp;ldquo;Christ alone&amp;rdquo;) Soli Deo gloria (&amp;ldquo;glory to God alone&amp;rdquo;) These statements have been used both to describe what Luther and the other reformers believed as well as to discern what the Bible does and does not teach. Because we often see the five solas listed out in bullet points, we often do not consider the relationships between them.</description></item><item><title>Please Pass the Pomegranate. Understanding the Nature of Sin in Genesis 3.</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/understanding-sin-from-genesis3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/understanding-sin-from-genesis3/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The Devil Made Me Do It&amp;rdquo;? First, consider who or what was involved in making Eve sin. One of the answers is clearly Satan in the form of the serpent (see Genesis 3:1). It is Satan who asks the infamous question &amp;ldquo;Hath God said&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; and causes Eve to doubt the words of God. It is important to recognize, however, that Satan is not the only thing that drives Eve to sin.</description></item></channel></rss>