<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Genesis on Bible Research</title>
    <link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/genesis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Genesis on Bible Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/genesis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cain &amp; Abel</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/cain-and-abel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/cain-and-abel/</guid>
      <description>Why was Abel&amp;rsquo;s sacrifice accepted while Cain&amp;rsquo;s was not?
Genesis 4:1-15 describes the infamous story of Cain and Abel. In this story, two brothers, Cain (a &amp;ldquo;tiller of the ground&amp;rdquo;) and Abel (a &amp;ldquo;keeper of flocks&amp;rdquo;), bring a sacrifice before God (see Genesis 4:2-3). Verses three and four tell us that Cain brings &amp;ldquo;an offering of the fruit of the ground&amp;rdquo; and Abel brings &amp;ldquo;the firstlings of his flock and their fat portions&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is Canaan Cursed Rather than Ham?</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/canaan-and-ham/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/canaan-and-ham/</guid>
      <description>Characteristic of the strange stories in Genesis, the story of Shem, Ham (and Canaan), and Japheth in Genesis 9:18-27 is the subject of much debate. Of particular interest is this: Why does Noah curse Canaan (Ham&amp;rsquo;s son) if Ham was the one who perpetrated the crime in question?
The text does not give us enough details to know exactly why, but I think there are a few things we can conclude from the passage:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Satan or Serpent? Understanding the Protevangelium.</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/defending-protevangelium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/defending-protevangelium/</guid>
      <description>Are we right to interpret Genesis 3:15 as applying to Satan?
I was recently reading through Genesis and paused when I got to Genesis 3:14-15. I have always been taught that Genesis 3:15 was directed not at the physical serpent (that is, the creature itself), but the spiritual &amp;lsquo;serpent&amp;rsquo; (who is Satan). But in my recent reading, I asked myself: Are we right to interpret Genesis 3:15 in this way?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please Pass the Pomegranate. Understanding the Nature of Sin in Genesis 3.</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/understanding-sin-from-genesis3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/understanding-sin-from-genesis3/</guid>
      <description>Just three short chapters into the narrative of God&amp;rsquo;s redemptive plan, we find Adam and Eve in the Garden of Eden, clothed with fig leaves and damning themselves and their children to a life separated from God. There are two observations about the story in Genesis 3 that I wish to make which will help us better understand the nature of sin.
First, consider who or what was involved in making Eve sin.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>