<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Genesis on Bible Research</title>
    <link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/genesis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Genesis on Bible Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/genesis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cain &amp; Abel</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/cain-and-abel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/cain-and-abel/</guid>
      <description>Genesis 4:1-15 describes the infamous story of Cain and Abel. In this story, two brothers, Cain (a &amp;ldquo;tiller of the ground&amp;rdquo;) and Abel (a &amp;ldquo;keeper of flocks&amp;rdquo;), bring a sacrifice before God (see Genesis 4:2-3). Verses three and four tell us that Cain brings &amp;ldquo;an offering of the fruit of the ground&amp;rdquo; and Abel brings &amp;ldquo;the firstlings of his flock and their fat portions&amp;rdquo;. The end of verse four and beginning of verse five reads: &amp;ldquo;And the LORD had regard for Abel and for his offering; but for Cain and for his offering He had no regard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is Canaan Cursed Rather than Ham?</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/canaan-and-ham/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/canaan-and-ham/</guid>
      <description>The text does not give us enough details to know exactly why, but I think there are a few things we can conclude from the passage:
 Part of the reason some readers take issue with this passage is that they think Ham is getting off without punishment for his offense. The punishment that fell to Canaan, however, would have felt like a punishment to Ham as well. His line was not blessed and one of his sons was cursed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Satan or Serpent? Understanding the Protevangelium.</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/defending-protevangelium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/defending-protevangelium/</guid>
      <description>I was recently reading through Genesis and paused when I got to Genesis 3:14-15. I have always been taught that Genesis 3:15 was directed not at the physical serpent (that is, the creature itself), but the spiritual &amp;lsquo;serpent&amp;rsquo; (who is Satan). But in my recent reading, I asked myself: Are we right to interpret Genesis 3:15 in this way? This post contains my conclusion on the subject after thought and investigation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please Pass the Pomegranate. Understanding the Nature of Sin in Genesis 3.</title>
      <link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/understanding-sin-from-genesis3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2017 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/understanding-sin-from-genesis3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The Devil Made Me Do It&amp;rdquo;? First, consider who or what was involved in making Eve sin. One of the answers is clearly Satan in the form of the serpent (see Genesis 3:1). It is Satan who asks the infamous question &amp;ldquo;Hath God said&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; and causes Eve to doubt the words of God. It is important to recognize, however, that Satan is not the only thing that drives Eve to sin.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>