<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bible on Bible Research</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/tags/bible/</link><description>Recent content in Bible on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//bible.hightower.space/tags/bible/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>False Grounds for Assurance of Salvation (part 1)</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/false-grounds-for-assurance-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/false-grounds-for-assurance-1/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Oh listen, do you love the Word of God? There&amp;rsquo;s no greater proof that you have really passed from death unto life than if you have an insatiable love for the Word of God.&amp;quot;1 Preface A Warning Before continuing, I encourage you to read the warning here.
If you are looking for the grounds of assurance of salvation (the means by which we can know that we are saved), I don&amp;rsquo;t have any to offer you right now and sincerely ask that you stop reading.</description></item><item><title>A Deadly Lifestyle (part 2): How I Feel About Church and the Bible Right Now</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/deadly-lifestyle-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/deadly-lifestyle-part-2/</guid><description>This is a follow up to the first &amp;ldquo;Deadly Lifestyle&amp;rdquo; post.
The Situation It is very difficult for me to read/study the Bible right now. Here is what happens almost every time I open the Bible:
I pray As you will see below, I really need help! I start reading for example, I recently read Acts 8 I notice something fascinating/interesting In Acts 8, it is interesting that Simon the Magician is said to have &amp;ldquo;believed&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;being baptized, he continued on with Philip&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (Acts 8:13) and yet Peter harshly rebukes him for trying to buy the free gift of God and calls him to repent (Acts 8:21-23).</description></item><item><title>A Deadly Lifestyle: How I Feel About Church and the Bible Right Now</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/deadly-lifestyle/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/deadly-lifestyle/</guid><description>For the past year, going to church and reading the bible has felt like this:
I am shackled in a prison. I am periodically given enough &amp;lsquo;food&amp;rsquo; to live (I say &amp;lsquo;food&amp;rsquo; because some of it is inedible or undesirable (raw, rotting meat, bones, lard, etc.))&amp;hellip; but getting the food is difficult because the shackle on my neck has small protrusions or hooks on the inside designed to create small lacerations on my neck if I strain against the shackle too much.</description></item><item><title>Why Pray Using the Bible</title><link>//bible.hightower.space/posts/why-pray-the-bible/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bible.hightower.space/posts/why-pray-the-bible/</guid><description>As I describe here, my prayer life used to be pitiful. My prayers where repetitive, virtually meaningless and unguided ramblings that God would &amp;ldquo;be with&amp;rdquo; someone (whatever that means). It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until I heard a sermon on using the Bible to guide our prayers that I was able to significantly change the way I pray.
In this sermon, the pastor argued that we should use a passage of scripture to guide our prayers.</description></item></channel></rss>