<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Faith on Bible Research</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/tags/faith/</link><description>Recent content in Faith on Bible Research</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bible.hightower.space/tags/faith/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Must I Do to be Saved?</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/how-can-man-be-saved/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/how-can-man-be-saved/</guid><description>This blog post contains what I consider to be big, weighty questions (with very few answers). If you choose to keep reading, please skim this post first: https://bible.hightower.space/posts/2020-warning/.
What must I do to be saved?
Seriously, what must I do to be saved? I&amp;rsquo;m so confused and overwhelmed by a whirl-wind of comments and responses on this question (both from inside and outside the Bible) that I honestly don&amp;rsquo;t know what the answer is right now.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Temptation of Jesus in Light of Matthew 3:17</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/temptation-of-jesus-matthew/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/temptation-of-jesus-matthew/</guid><description>I recently heard a sermon on the temptation of Jesus (Matthew 4:1-11) in which the pastor said something that caught my attention, got me thinking, and led me to what I think is a deeper, richer understanding of this passage. While the pastor did not say what I am about to say explicitly, he hinted in its general direction and I am very grateful not just for this sermon, but also for his faithful ministry of the word of God.</description></item><item><title>"For our sake also" - The Beauty and Grace of Divine Revelation</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/romans-4-23-and-24/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/romans-4-23-and-24/</guid><description>I was reading the book of Romans and Romans 4:23-25 jumped out at me; it reads:
&amp;ldquo;Now not for his sake only was it written that it was credited to him, but for our sake also, to whom it will be credited, as those who believe in Him who raised Jesus our Lord from the dead, He who was delivered over because of our transgressions, and was raised because of our justification.</description></item><item><title>A Man Worth Trusting</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/a-man-worth-trusting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/a-man-worth-trusting/</guid><description>I was studying John 18:1-11 with some friends and was struck by something one of my friends said. We had just discussed John 18:3 where the word &amp;ldquo;σπεῖραν&amp;rdquo;1could mean either a tenth of a legion (a legion was 6,000 men, so this would mean 600 men were coming to arrest Jesus) or used as Polybius referring to 200 men2. Either way, you likely have a good number of men coming to arrest Jesus.</description></item><item><title>Pope Clement I on Salvation</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/first-pope-message/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/first-pope-message/</guid><description>Here is an excerpt from Pope Clement I in his First Epistle to the Corinthian Church:
&amp;ldquo;All these [referring to Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob], therefore, were highly honoured, and made great, not for their own sake, or for their own works, or for the righteousness which they wrought, but through the operation of His will. And we, too, being called by His will in Christ Jesus, are not justified by ourselves, nor by our own wisdom, or understanding, or godliness, or works which we have wrought in holiness of heart; but by that faith through which, from the beginning, Almighty God has justified all men; to whom be glory for ever and ever.</description></item><item><title>Three Aspects of Saving Faith</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/three-aspects-of-faith/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/three-aspects-of-faith/</guid><description>Introduction The three aspects of saving faith identified by the reformers are notitia, assensus, and fiducia.1For the reformers, saving faith was made up of each of these aspects. Possessing one or two of them does not mean you are saved. All three are necessary and are together sufficient for salvation. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at each of these aspects in more detail.
Three Aspects of Saving Faith Notitia Notitia refers to the comprehension of data or content that is to be believed.</description></item><item><title>Three Evidences that Baptism Is Not Necessary for Salvation</title><link>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/baptism-and-salvation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 06:21:22 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://bible.hightower.space/posts/baptism-and-salvation/</guid><description>There are some passages in scripture which appear, at first glance, to be saying that baptism is necessary for salvation (for example Mark 16:16, Acts 2:37-38, Galatians 3:27). In reformed, protestant circles, there are counter-arguments given for all of these passages (which I think are convincing and have sound Biblical grounds). I here present, however, three evidences from scripture that salvation does not require baptism. I would be curious how someone who believes that baptism is required for salvation would respond (you can contact me if you are such a person).</description></item></channel></rss>